ep_summary,air_date,ep_nums,ep_title,episode,season,year,Entities,MoveFromCity,MoveFromCountry,MoveToCity,MoveToCountry,NumBlanks,NumWords
"Perry and Cheryl Meriot are Edmonton Alberta natives who are sick and tired of the brutal winters there. Perry's job as an Airline baggage handler means he works outside during even the worst weather. After a trip to Punta Cana in the Dominican Republic, the couple decided to save up and buy a second home there. They want a 2 bedroom condo on a 2nd floor in a gated community that's close to the beach. But they have a very firm budget of $150,000 which means they may not be able to buy as close to the beach as they'd like. The first place their real estate agent Sabine Gruss takes them to see is a model unit in a large complex with a big pool. The complex is about 5 minutes walking from the beach. The unit has 1 bedroom and 1 and a half bathrooms in 1000 square feet. It's listed at $115,000 but upgrading to a second floor unit means the price would be closer to $120,000. They like the large patio and the updated kitchen but none of the furniture or appliances are included, so that would be an extra expense. They also want two bedrooms in case they have guests. The second place Sabine takes them to see is a condo in a smaller complex. It's about 10 minutes walking from the beach. The condo is on the second floor, and has 2 bedrooms and 2 bathrooms in 1100 square feet. It's listed at the top of their price range, at $150,000. They like the small balcony but not the view of the countryside or the small pool in the complex. But Cheryl loves the updated kitchen and bathrooms, and having 2 bedrooms is a big plus. The third place they look at is actually a single family home. It's priced at $148,000 and has 2 bedrooms and 2 bathrooms in 1500 square feet. The house itself is older and would need some work in the kitchen and bathrooms. And because it's larger they would have to buy more funriture to fill it up. But it's part of a community with an amazing pool and bar area that both cheryl and perry love. The only other drawback is that it is about a 10 minute drive from the",21-Feb-10,S12E11,"Canadian Couple Buys a Vacation Home in Punta Cana, Dominican Republic",11,12,2010,"[('Cheryl Meriot', 10, 23, 'PERSON'), ('Edmonton Alberta', 28, 44, 'PERSON'), ('winters', 90, 97, 'DATE'), ('Perry', 105, 110, 'PERSON'), ('Airline', 123, 130, 'ORG'), ('Punta Cana', 217, 227, 'ORG'), ('the Dominican Republic', 231, 253, 'GPE'), ('second', 295, 301, 'ORDINAL'), ('2', 326, 327, 'CARDINAL'), ('2nd', 347, 350, 'ORDINAL'), ('150,000', 442, 449, 'MONEY'), ('first', 532, 537, 'ORDINAL'), ('Sabine Gruss', 568, 580, 'PERSON'), ('about 5 minutes', 666, 681, 'TIME'), ('1', 719, 720, 'CARDINAL'), ('1 and a half', 733, 745, 'CARDINAL'), ('1000 square feet', 759, 775, 'QUANTITY'), ('115,000', 793, 800, 'MONEY'), ('second', 820, 826, 'ORDINAL'), ('120,000', 874, 881, 'MONEY'), ('two', 1037, 1040, 'CARDINAL'), ('second', 1080, 1086, 'ORDINAL'), ('about 10 minutes', 1156, 1172, 'TIME'), ('second', 1217, 1223, 'ORDINAL'), ('2', 1239, 1240, 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 1254, 1255, 'CARDINAL'), ('1100 square feet', 1269, 1285, 'QUANTITY'), ('150,000', 1336, 1343, 'MONEY'), ('Cheryl', 1447, 1453, 'PERSON'), ('2', 1506, 1507, 'CARDINAL'), ('third', 1536, 1541, 'ORDINAL'), ('148,000', 1611, 1618, 'MONEY'), ('2', 1627, 1628, 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 1642, 1643, 'CARDINAL'), ('1500 square feet', 1657, 1673, 'QUANTITY'), ('10 minute', 1975, 1984, 'TIME')]",Edmonton,Canada,Punta Cana,Dominican Republic,0,383
"Ken and Donna Richardson live in Conway South Carolina with their maltese dog, Oscar. Ken recently retired and wants to buy a 2nd home in his favorite fishing spot, Nosara Costa Rica. Even though Donna has never been there, she is feeling adventurous and is willing to join Ken in the search. They want a 3 bed, 3 bath home with an open floorplan, a pool and an ocean view. They also want to buy a place close to the beach. They have a budget of $700,000, and they've given themselves just 3 days to complete their search. Their real estate agent Bram Shook knows it might be difficult for them to find a place that's both close to the beach that also has ocean views, since in Nosara there is a wildlife refuge that separates all the homes from the beach. The first place he takes them to see is a 10 minute drive from the beach and has 3 bedrooms and 3 baths in 3000 square feet. It's listed for $525,000. The home has a nice pool and amazing ocean views, though Donna is worried about her grandson's safety since the patio has very little railing. They like all three bedrooms, but they aren't crazy about how far the home is from the beach. Later that same day Bram takes them to see a 3400 square foot, 4 bed, 3 bath home that's listed for $650,000. This home is a 10 minute walk to the beach, but it has a fantastic pool area with an outdoor bar and kitchen. They aren't crazy about the small guest rooms and the bright tropical paint colors but they do like the master bedroom and the ocean view from the rooftop deck.The next day Bram takes them to see a home that's a 2 minute walk from the beach. Listed for $450,000, the house has 3 bedrooms and 2 bathrooms in 1250 square feet. Ken and Donna like being closer to the beach but they aren't crazy about the inside of the home and the fact that there are no ocean views. They both think the furniture, countertops and appliances would need to be replaced, and the home is much smaller than the other two they saw. With one day left to make t",27-Jan-10,S12E12,South Carolina Retirees Buy 2nd Home in Costa Rica,12,12,2010,"[('Ken', 0, 3, 'PERSON'), ('Donna Richardson', 8, 24, 'PERSON'), ('Conway South Carolina', 33, 54, 'GPE'), ('Oscar', 79, 84, 'PERSON'), ('Ken', 86, 89, 'PERSON'), ('2nd', 126, 129, 'ORDINAL'), ('Nosara Costa Rica', 165, 182, 'GPE'), ('Donna', 196, 201, 'PERSON'), ('Ken', 274, 277, 'PERSON'), ('3', 305, 306, 'CARDINAL'), ('3', 312, 313, 'CARDINAL'), ('700,000', 447, 454, 'MONEY'), ('3 days', 490, 496, 'DATE'), ('Bram Shook', 547, 557, 'PERSON'), ('Nosara', 678, 684, 'GPE'), ('first', 761, 766, 'ORDINAL'), ('10 minute', 799, 808, 'TIME'), ('3', 838, 839, 'CARDINAL'), ('3', 853, 854, 'CARDINAL'), ('3000 square feet', 864, 880, 'QUANTITY'), ('525,000', 899, 906, 'MONEY'), ('Donna', 965, 970, 'PERSON'), ('three', 1065, 1070, 'CARDINAL'), ('Later that same day', 1145, 1164, 'DATE'), ('Bram', 1165, 1169, 'PERSON'), ('3400 square foot', 1190, 1206, 'QUANTITY'), ('4', 1208, 1209, 'CARDINAL'), ('3', 1215, 1216, 'CARDINAL'), ('650,000', 1246, 1253, 'MONEY'), ('10 minute', 1270, 1279, 'TIME'), ('The next day', 1525, 1537, 'DATE'), ('Bram', 1538, 1542, 'PERSON'), ('2 minute', 1577, 1585, 'TIME'), ('450,000', 1619, 1626, 'MONEY'), ('house', 1632, 1637, 'ORG'), ('3', 1642, 1643, 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 1657, 1658, 'CARDINAL'), ('1250 square feet', 1672, 1688, 'QUANTITY'), ('Ken', 1690, 1693, 'PERSON'), ('Donna', 1698, 1703, 'PERSON'), ('two', 1959, 1962, 'CARDINAL'), ('one day', 1978, 1985, 'DATE')]","Conway, South Carolina",United States,Nosara,Costa Rica,0,382
"Dan and Andrea Layden (30's) are history buffs who live in Philadelphia with their two small children. Andrea can trace her family history back to 18th century Italy. Now she and Dan want to introduce their children to her old world roots by buying a vacation home in the Abruzzo region of Italy where both Andrea's mother and grandmother are from. They have a budget of 100,000 Euro (equal to $140,000). They want a charming Italian cottage that has 2 bedrooms, 1 bathroom, some outdoor space, and a working kitchen. The first place Dan and Andrea and their kids go to see with their agent, Nicola Di Girolamo, is at the top of a very windy road in the Abruzzo region. The home has 2 beds and 1 bath in 1300 sq. ft., and it's listed for the equivalent of $116,000. The exterior of the home is built with stone from the region, but the owners have drilled parts of the wall which has created huge cracks inside the living room. The kitchen is outdated and has very old appliances but at least the bedrooms are a good size and have a nice view. They like that it comes with 1.24 acres of land, but they aren't crazy about the windy road and how much work the home needs. The second place Nikki takes them all to see is in a more accessible area, close to the lake in the town of Penne. It's a 2 bed, 1 bath, 860 square foot cottage listed for the equivalent of $163,000. They like the charming rounded windows and original fireplace, but the kitchen and bathroom are very outdated. They don't mind the small bedrooms that much, but they would like a better view of the half acre of land the house sits on. The third place Nikki takes them to see is near the town of Citta S'Angelo. It's a one-room 450 square foot cottage with a small kitchen and bathroom, that shares 3 acres of land with an old ruin. They like the idea that they could live in the small finished cottage while building a larger home on the site of the ruin. They also like the views and the amount of land, but Dan is worried it wil",3-Feb-10,S12E08,Dan and Andrea Want a Family-Friendly Vacation Cottage in the Scenic Abruzzo Region of Italy,8,12,2010,"[('Dan', 0, 3, 'PERSON'), ('Andrea Layden', 8, 21, 'PERSON'), ('Philadelphia', 59, 71, 'GPE'), ('two', 83, 86, 'CARDINAL'), ('Andrea', 103, 109, 'PERSON'), ('18th', 147, 151, 'ORDINAL'), ('Italy', 160, 165, 'GPE'), ('Dan', 179, 182, 'PERSON'), ('Abruzzo', 272, 279, 'PERSON'), ('Italy', 290, 295, 'GPE'), ('Andrea', 307, 313, 'PERSON'), ('100,000', 371, 378, 'CARDINAL'), ('140,000', 395, 402, 'MONEY'), ('Italian', 426, 433, 'NORP'), ('2', 451, 452, 'CARDINAL'), ('1', 463, 464, 'CARDINAL'), ('first', 522, 527, 'ORDINAL'), ('Dan', 534, 537, 'PERSON'), ('Andrea', 542, 548, 'PERSON'), ('Nicola Di Girolamo', 592, 610, 'PERSON'), ('Abruzzo', 654, 661, 'ORG'), ('2', 683, 684, 'CARDINAL'), ('1', 694, 695, 'CARDINAL'), ('1300', 704, 708, 'DATE'), ('ft.', 713, 716, 'PERSON'), ('116,000', 757, 764, 'MONEY'), ('1.24 acres', 1073, 1083, 'QUANTITY'), ('second', 1174, 1180, 'ORDINAL'), ('Nikki', 1187, 1192, 'ORG'), ('Penne', 1278, 1283, 'PERSON'), ('2', 1292, 1293, 'CARDINAL'), ('1', 1299, 1300, 'CARDINAL'), ('860 square foot', 1307, 1322, 'QUANTITY'), ('163,000', 1361, 1368, 'MONEY'), ('the half acre', 1564, 1577, 'QUANTITY'), ('third', 1609, 1614, 'ORDINAL'), ('Nikki', 1621, 1626, 'ORG'), (""Citta S'Angelo"", 1665, 1679, 'PERSON'), ('one', 1688, 1691, 'CARDINAL'), ('450 square foot', 1697, 1712, 'QUANTITY'), ('3 acres', 1768, 1775, 'QUANTITY'), ('Dan', 1979, 1982, 'PERSON')]",Philadelphia,United States,Abruzzo,Italy,0,379
"Kevin and Kim Dooley (40's) live with their 4 kids, Taylor, Tucker, Callahan and Annabel in the small town of Avon, Indiana. For the past 10 years the family has been involved with peace initiatives in the ancient city of Fes, Morocco. They're currently teaching Moroccan women how to make a living by using scraps of fabric to make purses. Since the family is visiting Morocco more and more frequently, Kevin and Kim want to buy a 2nd home there. They want a place with a rooftop terrace, a decent kitchen, 3 or 4 bedrooms and western style bathrooms. They have a budget of $250,000, and Kim is hoping to find something move-in ready while Kevin thinks it would be fun to buy a rundown place he can fix-up himself. Kevin is going alone to search for a home, so Kim can stay behind with the kids who are in the middle of the school year. The first place David Kellar, the Dooley's real estate agent, takes Kevin to see is a 2400 sqaure foot, 3 bedroom, 3 bathroom Dar (house or palace) listed for $210,000. This restored traditonal-style home is covered in Zellige tile and intricate plaster work. Kevin likes the size and layout of the rooms, but there is no working kitchen or bathrooms and the rooftop deck doesn't have the best views. The second place David takes Kevin to see is a complete fixer listed for $40,000. It has room for 2 bedrooms and 2 bathrooms in about 1700 square feet. Kevin loves the low price and the idea of restoring the entire home and customising it to his family's needs. At the same time, he's worried that it might be too big of a project and it might take too long to complete. David can't make it for the 3rd house tour so he sends along his cultural liasion, Abdullah, instead. Abdullah takes Kevin to see a completely restored, 1800 square foot, 4 bedroom, 2.5 bath house that's priced at $210,000. Kevin likes the finished kitchen and the view from the rooftop terrace, but the bathroom has unusually low ceilings and there's nothing for him to really fix up. Afte",6-Jan-10,S12E09,Kevin and Kim Want a 2nd Home in Fes Morocco to Use as a Base for Humanitarian Aid,9,12,2010,"[('Kevin', 0, 5, 'PERSON'), ('Kim Dooley', 10, 20, 'PERSON'), ('4', 44, 45, 'CARDINAL'), ('Taylor', 52, 58, 'PERSON'), ('Tucker', 60, 66, 'PERSON'), ('Callahan', 68, 76, 'PERSON'), ('Annabel', 81, 88, 'PERSON'), ('Avon', 110, 114, 'GPE'), ('Indiana', 116, 123, 'GPE'), ('the past 10 years', 129, 146, 'DATE'), ('Fes', 222, 225, 'GPE'), ('Morocco', 227, 234, 'GPE'), ('Moroccan', 263, 271, 'NORP'), ('Morocco', 370, 377, 'GPE'), ('Kevin', 404, 409, 'PERSON'), ('Kim', 414, 417, 'PERSON'), ('2nd', 432, 435, 'ORDINAL'), ('3', 508, 509, 'CARDINAL'), ('4', 513, 514, 'CARDINAL'), ('250,000', 576, 583, 'MONEY'), ('Kim', 589, 592, 'PERSON'), ('Kevin', 641, 646, 'PERSON'), ('Kevin', 716, 721, 'PERSON'), ('Kim', 762, 765, 'PERSON'), ('first', 842, 847, 'ORDINAL'), ('David Kellar', 854, 866, 'PERSON'), ('Dooley', 872, 878, 'ORG'), ('Kevin', 906, 911, 'PERSON'), ('2400', 924, 928, 'CARDINAL'), ('3', 942, 943, 'CARDINAL'), ('3', 953, 954, 'CARDINAL'), ('210,000', 998, 1005, 'MONEY'), ('Zellige', 1057, 1064, 'GPE'), ('Kevin', 1098, 1103, 'PERSON'), ('second', 1243, 1249, 'ORDINAL'), ('David', 1256, 1261, 'PERSON'), ('Kevin', 1268, 1273, 'PERSON'), ('40,000', 1313, 1319, 'MONEY'), ('2', 1337, 1338, 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 1352, 1353, 'CARDINAL'), ('about 1700 square feet', 1367, 1389, 'QUANTITY'), ('Kevin', 1391, 1396, 'PERSON'), ('David', 1610, 1615, 'PERSON'), ('the 3rd house', 1634, 1647, 'ORG'), ('Abdullah', 1693, 1701, 'PERSON'), ('Abdullah', 1712, 1720, 'PERSON'), ('Kevin', 1727, 1732, 'PERSON'), ('1800 square foot', 1763, 1779, 'QUANTITY'), ('4', 1781, 1782, 'CARDINAL'), ('2.5', 1792, 1795, 'CARDINAL'), ('bath house', 1796, 1806, 'ORG'), ('210,000', 1825, 1832, 'MONEY'), ('Kevin', 1834, 1839, 'PERSON')]","Avon, Indiana",United States,Fes,Morocco,0,364
"Cousins Rydell and Craig (30's) have decided to purchase a vacation condo together and fiancee Candace and wife Jamie are thrilled about the idea. They're focusing their search on Ambergris Caye in Belize so they'll be able to escape Calgary's cold winters. Since it's a vacation condo, location and amenities are high on their list. They want to be close to the water, have the place already nicely furnished and have enough room to relax. Ideally they're looking for a two bedroom place and don't want to spend more than 300,000 US dollars. Real estate agent Steve Reid joins them on their search and first shows them a two bedroom, two bath condo in Bermuda Beach. It's listed for 275 thousand dollars and it's 1000 square feet. It's brand new, has an ocean view, and even a spa tub in the master bedroom, but it has a pretty small kitchen, balcony and eating area. The outside pool and BBQ area are great, but there's also some ongoing construction. The guys check in with the girls via computer at the end of their day and the girls aren't thrilled with the size of the place. The next place that Steve takes them to see is a two bedroom, two bath condo at Brightwaters Beach Resort listed for 279 thousand dollars. It's a bit larger at 1100 square feet and there are great ocean views, but the decor is outdated and it's far from town. This time the girls aren't so sure about such a remote place. So the next day the guys are back on the hunt. Steve takes them to Las Terrazas to see a condo listed for 279 thousand dollars that's a bit under 1000 square feet. The guys are impressed with the grounds and the spa-like atmosphere, but they aren't thrilled when Steve tells them that the condo only has one bedroom. But it's beautifully decorated, updated and steps from the beach. When Craig and Rydell call the girls via computer that evening, they just aren't so sure about the one bedroom. So which place will become these Canadians' piece of paradise?",24-Jan-10,S12E04,"Two Cousins Search for a Shared Vacation Condo in Belize, and Check in With Their Wife and Girlfriend Via I-Chat for Their Feedback After Each Tour",4,12,2010,"[('Cousins Rydell', 0, 14, 'ORG'), ('Craig', 19, 24, 'PERSON'), ('Jamie', 112, 117, 'PERSON'), ('Ambergris Caye', 180, 194, 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Belize', 198, 204, 'GPE'), ('Calgary', 234, 241, 'GPE'), ('winters', 249, 256, 'DATE'), ('two', 471, 474, 'CARDINAL'), ('more than 300,000 US dollars', 513, 541, 'MONEY'), ('Steve Reid', 561, 571, 'PERSON'), ('first', 603, 608, 'ORDINAL'), ('two', 622, 625, 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 635, 638, 'CARDINAL'), ('Bermuda Beach', 653, 666, 'GPE'), ('275 thousand dollars', 684, 704, 'MONEY'), ('1000 square feet', 714, 730, 'QUANTITY'), ('BBQ', 890, 893, 'ORG'), ('the end of their day', 1003, 1023, 'DATE'), ('Steve', 1102, 1107, 'PERSON'), ('two', 1131, 1134, 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 1144, 1147, 'CARDINAL'), ('Brightwaters Beach Resort', 1162, 1187, 'FAC'), ('279 thousand dollars', 1199, 1219, 'MONEY'), ('1100 square feet', 1242, 1258, 'QUANTITY'), ('the next day', 1407, 1419, 'DATE'), ('Steve', 1451, 1456, 'PERSON'), ('Las Terrazas', 1471, 1483, 'GPE'), ('279 thousand dollars', 1510, 1530, 'MONEY'), ('1000 square feet', 1550, 1566, 'QUANTITY'), ('Steve', 1667, 1672, 'PERSON'), ('one', 1708, 1711, 'CARDINAL'), ('Craig', 1792, 1797, 'PERSON'), ('Rydell', 1802, 1808, 'ORG'), ('that evening', 1837, 1849, 'TIME'), ('one', 1886, 1889, 'CARDINAL'), ('Canadians', 1932, 1941, 'NORP')]",Calgary,Canada,Ambergris Caye,Belize,0,354
"Salinas, California high school math teacher, Michelle Moser, wants to buy a vacation home in the birthplace of grandmother: the southern region of Calabria, Italy. She's looking for a place with enough space for her and guests, ocean views, a terrace and a kitchen suitable for cooking up wonderful Italian pasta dishes. She hopes to find a place in a small town or village where she can walk to shops and restaurants. With a budget of about $100,000, she knows it will still be a challenge. The first place her agent, Tony Hackett, shows her is a partially renovated home in Santa Dominica Talao. Listed for $85,000, this place has 2 bedrooms, 1 bath and is 1,183 square feet. While there aren't any ocean views, this home has beautiful views of the mountains. The renovated parts of the house are well done, but a kitchen still needs to be installed and two rooms are in need of a complete remodel. The next house they look at is a home in the town of Scalea. Listed at $102,000, this place has 2 bedrooms, 2 bathrooms and is 700 square feet. Michelle likes the brick floors, wood beamed ceilings and the ocean and mountain views. She's particularly fond of a former escape tunnel that leads to the beach. On the downside, it needs work. The location and layout of the kitchen and second bathroom are oddly placed, there is some water damage, there are some strangely designed stairs and some of the rooms need a bit of a facelift. The last place they look at is back in Santa Dominica Talao, where they check out a 700 square foot, 2 bedroom, 1 bath home for $79,000. Michelle likes this home's layout and thinks it has the best view of the ocean. But, she feels the decor isn't very interesting and would have to plan on remodeling down the road. She also has concerns about the water damage. After weighing the pros and cons of all 3 properties, Michelle reaches her decision.",24-Jan-10,S12E05,"Californian Teacher Wants to Get in Touch With Her Roots and Buy a Vacation Home in Calabria, Italy (2nd Home in Calabria, Italy)",5,12,2010,"[('Salinas', 0, 7, 'GPE'), ('California', 9, 19, 'GPE'), ('Michelle Moser', 46, 60, 'PERSON'), ('Calabria', 148, 156, 'GPE'), ('Italy', 158, 163, 'GPE'), ('Italian', 300, 307, 'NORP'), ('about $100,000', 437, 451, 'MONEY'), ('first', 497, 502, 'ORDINAL'), ('Tony Hackett', 520, 532, 'PERSON'), ('Santa Dominica Talao', 577, 597, 'ORG'), ('85,000', 611, 617, 'MONEY'), ('2', 634, 635, 'CARDINAL'), ('1', 646, 647, 'CARDINAL'), ('1,183 square feet', 660, 677, 'QUANTITY'), ('two', 857, 860, 'CARDINAL'), ('Scalea', 955, 961, 'GPE'), ('102,000', 974, 981, 'MONEY'), ('2', 998, 999, 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 1010, 1011, 'CARDINAL'), ('700 square feet', 1029, 1044, 'QUANTITY'), ('Michelle', 1046, 1054, 'PERSON'), ('second', 1284, 1290, 'ORDINAL'), ('Santa Dominica Talao', 1474, 1494, 'GPE'), ('a 700 square foot', 1517, 1534, 'QUANTITY'), ('2', 1536, 1537, 'CARDINAL'), ('1', 1547, 1548, 'CARDINAL'), ('79,000', 1564, 1570, 'MONEY'), ('Michelle', 1572, 1580, 'PERSON'), ('3', 1838, 1839, 'CARDINAL'), ('Michelle', 1852, 1860, 'PERSON')]","Salinas, California",United States,Calabria,Italy,0,339
"Evan, who is from the Midwest, and Maria-Isabel who is from Nicaragua, own a restaurant together in historic Granada, Nicaragua. They are ready to buy a home but don't exactly agree on where. Evan wants to be as close to their restaurant in the city center as he can get, while Maria-Isabel is seeking a quieter, possibly more distant refuge. They both agree on size: 2 bedrooms plus an office, and on style: they like historic homes, and appreciate architectural authenticity. They also like to entertain and would like a hip space to do so. Real Estate Agent Sean Dennis shows them an historic home in the heart of town. Evan and Maria-Isabel love the home's authentic details and view of the cathedral, but Maria-Isabel is concerned about noise. Next Sean shows them a Colonial Reproduction a few minutes outside the center of town. Evan and Maria-Isabel are charmed by the fine finishes, courtyard pool, and rooftop deck, but they are disappointed in the home's lack of authenticity -- since it is a reproduction -- and worry about its ability to retain its value. Also, Maria-Isabel is still hoping for something more tranquil. Finally, Sean shows them a private island home on the lake. He explains that the lake is home to 365 ''isletas'' or private islands, and that this one could be their very own. The island home has a 2 bedroom home, and a 2 bedroom guest house, and beautiful natural landscaping. Evan and Maria-Isabel are wowed by the property, but concerned about the price, and the difficult commute (by boat). They weigh the pros and cons of each property, and ultimately choose the first house they saw - the authentic colonial in the heart of town. Their restaurant is just 2 blocks away, they love the proximity to friends and to all that the city has to offer, and Maria-Isabel finds that when the centuries old doors are shut, she cannot hear the noisy street outside. They love their new haven in the city.",17-Jan-10,S12E03,"Evan and Maria-Isabel Set Out to a Find Home in Historic Granada, Nicaragua That is Both Relaxing, and Convenient to the Restaurant They Own",3,12,2010,"[('Midwest', 22, 29, 'LOC'), ('Maria-Isabel', 35, 47, 'PERSON'), ('Nicaragua', 60, 69, 'GPE'), ('Granada', 109, 116, 'GPE'), ('Nicaragua', 118, 127, 'GPE'), ('Maria-Isabel', 278, 290, 'PERSON'), ('2', 368, 369, 'CARDINAL'), ('Sean Dennis', 561, 572, 'PERSON'), ('Maria-Isabel', 632, 644, 'PERSON'), ('Maria-Isabel', 710, 722, 'PERSON'), ('Maria-Isabel', 845, 857, 'PERSON'), ('Maria-Isabel', 1075, 1087, 'PERSON'), ('Sean', 1142, 1146, 'NORP'), ('365', 1230, 1233, 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 1331, 1332, 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 1353, 1354, 'CARDINAL'), ('Maria-Isabel', 1420, 1432, 'PERSON'), ('first', 1601, 1606, 'ORDINAL'), ('2', 1694, 1695, 'CARDINAL'), ('Maria-Isabel', 1787, 1799, 'PERSON')]",Granada,Nicaragua,Granada,Nicaragua,0,337
"Scott Medina is relocating from Miami to the Dominican Republic to kick-start his real estate business into high gear and to return to his Caribbean roots. He's looking to set up shop and find a condo in the high-end beach district of Punta Cana, known for its white sand beaches and luxury hotels. Scott's main priority is location- he'd love to be able to walk to the beach. He's also looking for a two-bedroom place so he can have a separate office and more storage, and he'd like a pool on the premises. He's hoping his real estate expertise will help him find all of these amenities in a 200 thousand dollar budget. Real estate agent and friend Frances Pimentel is going to help Scott on his search for the right place. The first condo that Frances shows Scott is a one-bedroom, one and a half bath condo right on a golf course. It's listed for 195 thousand dollars and is 1100 square feet. Scott is impressed with the high end details and the luxurious pool area, but he's concerned about the lack of office space and that it's a bit further from the beach than he would like. Next up is a two-bedroom, two-bath condo selling for 180 thousand dollars that's only five minutes from the beach. It's a bit larger than the first at 1200 square feet, and Scott loves the second bedroom and the rooftop terrace, but the fixtures are older and it might need some updating. The third place Scott sees is a two-bedroom, two-bath 1100 square foot condo priced at 150 thousand dollars. He loves the fact that it's brand new, but he's not thrilled with the ongoing construction close by. He's also impressed with the huge private deck, but the unit is a little bit further from the beach and it's a little bit smaller than the other two-bedroom condo. After seeing three terrific options, Scott needs to make his decision. Which condo will become his new Caribbean home?",10-Jan-10,S12E02,A Miami Real Estate Broker is Relocating to the Dominican Republic,2,12,2010,"[('Scott Medina', 0, 12, 'PERSON'), ('Miami', 32, 37, 'GPE'), ('the Dominican Republic', 41, 63, 'GPE'), ('Caribbean', 139, 148, 'LOC'), ('Punta Cana', 235, 245, 'FAC'), ('Scott', 299, 304, 'ORG'), ('two', 401, 404, 'CARDINAL'), ('200 thousand dollar', 593, 612, 'MONEY'), ('Frances Pimentel', 650, 666, 'PERSON'), ('Scott', 684, 689, 'PERSON'), ('first', 729, 734, 'ORDINAL'), ('Frances', 746, 753, 'PERSON'), ('Scott', 760, 765, 'PERSON'), ('one', 771, 774, 'CARDINAL'), ('one and a half', 784, 798, 'CARDINAL'), ('195 thousand dollars', 850, 870, 'MONEY'), ('1100 square feet', 878, 894, 'QUANTITY'), ('Scott', 896, 901, 'PERSON'), ('two', 1096, 1099, 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 1109, 1112, 'CARDINAL'), ('180 thousand dollars', 1136, 1156, 'MONEY'), ('only five minutes', 1164, 1181, 'TIME'), ('first', 1225, 1230, 'ORDINAL'), ('1200 square feet', 1234, 1250, 'QUANTITY'), ('Scott', 1256, 1261, 'PERSON'), ('second', 1272, 1278, 'ORDINAL'), ('third', 1376, 1381, 'ORDINAL'), ('Scott', 1388, 1393, 'PERSON'), ('two', 1404, 1407, 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 1417, 1420, 'CARDINAL'), ('1100 square foot', 1426, 1442, 'QUANTITY'), ('150 thousand dollars', 1459, 1479, 'MONEY'), ('two', 1727, 1730, 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 1759, 1764, 'CARDINAL'), ('Scott', 1783, 1788, 'PERSON'), ('Caribbean', 1849, 1858, 'NORP')]",Miami,United States,Punta Cana,Dominican Republic,0,335
"They say that opposites attract and for Jim and Loretta Swartz, married for 26 years, that's a fact. She's very low-key, and lets him handle all the family worries. But despite their differences in personality, they agree that the family deserves the vacation home they've been saving ten years to afford. They'd like to buy a place now for vacations, and ultimately retire there. Their house in the planned community of Columbia, Maryland is large and comfortable, but it's far from the soothing sounds of the ocean that Loretta loves so much. They're focusing their search on the small island of Roatan, off the coast of Honduras, because of its peaceful beaches, and unspoiled feel. They'd like three bedrooms, two bathrooms, and while Loretta would like to wake up to the surf in her back yard and sand in her toes, Jim thinks an ocean view property would be a better investment. Their budget is $800,000. The first place Realtor Mike Carter shows them has three bedrooms and two baths in 2,000 square feet. It's a new, oceanfront development with luxury finishes, and the condo is listed at $699,000. They love the oceanfront location, but feel like the condo lacks privacy from the neighbors. The second place they see is a single family home. It has ocean views, luxury finishes, and is listed for $775,000. It is much larger than the first, with four bedrooms, fouir baths, and 3,000 square feet. Jim and Loretta love the privacy and think the home is beautiful, but they're concerned about the long walk from the parking lot, especially since they plan to ultimately retire here. The third home is a 3,315 square foot, oceanfront condo with convenient parking. It has two bedrooms, three baths, and is listed for $769,000. Loretta loves this location the best, but it does not have the three bedrooms they were hoping for. Which one of these homes is the vacation destination they've been saving for and dreaming of for so many years?",13-Jan-10,S12E10,"The Swartz Family Saved for a Decade and Are Finally Ready to Buy Their Dream Vacation Home in Roatan, Honduras.",10,12,2010,"[('Jim', 40, 43, 'PERSON'), ('Loretta Swartz', 48, 62, 'PERSON'), ('26 years', 76, 84, 'DATE'), ('ten years', 285, 294, 'DATE'), ('Columbia', 421, 429, 'GPE'), ('Maryland', 431, 439, 'GPE'), ('Loretta', 522, 529, 'PERSON'), ('Roatan', 598, 604, 'GPE'), ('Honduras', 623, 631, 'GPE'), ('three', 698, 703, 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 714, 717, 'CARDINAL'), ('Loretta', 739, 746, 'ORG'), ('Jim', 820, 823, 'PERSON'), ('800,000', 901, 908, 'MONEY'), ('first', 914, 919, 'ORDINAL'), ('Realtor Mike Carter', 926, 945, 'PERSON'), ('three', 961, 966, 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 980, 983, 'CARDINAL'), ('2,000 square feet', 993, 1010, 'QUANTITY'), ('699,000', 1097, 1104, 'MONEY'), ('second', 1203, 1209, 'ORDINAL'), ('775,000', 1306, 1313, 'MONEY'), ('first', 1342, 1347, 'ORDINAL'), ('four', 1354, 1358, 'CARDINAL'), ('3,000 square feet', 1386, 1403, 'QUANTITY'), ('Jim', 1405, 1408, 'PERSON'), ('Loretta', 1413, 1420, 'PERSON'), ('third', 1593, 1598, 'ORDINAL'), ('3,315 square foot', 1609, 1626, 'QUANTITY'), ('two', 1677, 1680, 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 1691, 1696, 'QUANTITY'), ('769,000', 1723, 1730, 'MONEY'), ('three', 1795, 1800, 'CARDINAL'), ('so many years', 1929, 1942, 'DATE')]","Columbia, Maryland",United States,Roatan,Honduras,0,334
"Les and Anita (50's) are looking for a vacation home where they can escape Vancouver Island's cold winters and enjoy some tropical sunshine. They've fallen in love with Roatan, a small island off the coast of Honduras, so they've decided to purchase a home so they can spend several months there at a time rather than a week or two. Their daughter Kelsey and her fiance Dan are avid divers, so they're thrilled about the decision. Les and Anita are looking for a move-in ready 3 bedroom home that's large enough for the entire family and they really want a place that's close to the beach, has an ocean view and has room for a garden. Their budget is 300 thousand US dollars and they've enlisted Robert Sirois, a local realtor to assist them in their search. They've also created their own checklist to help rate each property and help them with their decision. The first place they see is a two bedroom, two bathroom 1800 square foot house in the Sunset Villa development listed for 289 thousand dollars. They really like the updated furnishings and the fact that it's only five minutes from the beach, but there is no ocean view. The next day Robert takes them to see a three bedroom, three bath 2100 square foot tri-level house in West End selling for 299 thousand dollars. They like the space and the nice views from each balcony, but the area in front of the house is being developed so there is no guarantee that they will keep their sea views. It also doesn't have a pool. The last place they see is an 1100 square foot 3 bedroom home in Turtle Crossing listed for 295 thousand dollars. It's close to the water, and has great views, but it's a bit small compared to the other properties and it needs some updating. Will Les and Anita's scoring system help them choose between these three tropical homes?",31-Jan-10,S12E06,Les and Anita are Looking for a Vacation Home on Roatan Island in Honduras to Escape Vancouver Island's Cold Winters,6,12,2010,"[('Anita', 8, 13, 'PERSON'), (""Vancouver Island's"", 75, 93, 'GPE'), ('winters', 99, 106, 'DATE'), ('Roatan', 169, 175, 'GPE'), ('Honduras', 209, 217, 'GPE'), ('several months', 275, 289, 'DATE'), ('week', 320, 324, 'DATE'), ('two', 328, 331, 'CARDINAL'), ('Kelsey', 348, 354, 'PERSON'), ('Dan', 370, 373, 'PERSON'), ('Anita', 439, 444, 'PERSON'), ('3', 477, 478, 'CARDINAL'), ('300 thousand US dollars', 651, 674, 'MONEY'), ('Robert Sirois', 696, 709, 'PERSON'), ('first', 866, 871, 'ORDINAL'), ('two', 892, 895, 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 905, 908, 'CARDINAL'), ('1800 square foot', 918, 934, 'QUANTITY'), ('Sunset Villa', 948, 960, 'GPE'), ('289 thousand dollars', 984, 1004, 'MONEY'), ('only five minutes', 1070, 1087, 'TIME'), ('Robert', 1145, 1151, 'PERSON'), ('three', 1172, 1177, 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 1187, 1192, 'CARDINAL'), ('2100 square foot', 1198, 1214, 'QUANTITY'), ('West End', 1234, 1242, 'LOC'), ('299 thousand dollars', 1255, 1275, 'MONEY'), ('1100 square foot', 1510, 1526, 'QUANTITY'), ('3', 1527, 1528, 'CARDINAL'), ('Turtle', 1545, 1551, 'GPE'), ('295 thousand dollars', 1572, 1592, 'MONEY'), ('Will Les', 1722, 1730, 'PERSON'), ('Anita', 1735, 1740, 'PERSON'), ('three', 1789, 1794, 'CARDINAL')]",Vancouver Island,Canada,Roatan,Honduras,0,327
"Ever since Juan Moreno imigrated from Cuenca, Ecuador to the United States, he's dreamed of eventually owning a home there. He and his wife, Diane, recently retired to Orlando Florida and are now ready to make that dream a reality. They're going to buy a second home in Cuenca. They're bringing their daughter Anna along to help them on this search. With a budget of $120,000, they want to get a 4 bedroom, 2 bath home. They would like a traditional Spanish style home with a view, but still have the modern amenities they have now, such as an open floor plan, built for earthquakes. Their agent, Monica Rodas, takes them to a 4 bed, 1 1/2 bath, house in 2,798 square feet listed for $135,000. It's an older home with a hacienda style layout. While Diane and Juan like the large backyard and how the house reminds Juan of his childhood home, they're concerned that the house is not only above their budget but will need some serious updating. So, Monica takes them to a brand new townhouse listed at $105,000. This place has 4 beds, 3 1/2 baths and is 1,800 square feet. They love all of the modern amenities, such as the open upgraded kitchen, the size of the rooms and the third floor bonus room. But, they wish it had a nice yard like the first house and are concerned about the safety of the staircase to the bonus room. They also wish it had a little more character. Monica then takes them to a house listed for $85,000 in a developing neighborhood. This place has 4 bedrooms and 2 1/2 baths and is 2,000 square feet. They like the easy to maintain yard, kitchen pantry and some of the wood details. But, the bedrooms are a bit small and they can hear the construction noise in the neighborhood. With three interesting options, which home will bring Juan's life full circle?",10-Feb-10,S12E13,Juan and Diane Fulfill Their Dream of Buying A Second Home In His Birthplace Of Cuenca Ecuador,13,12,2010,"[('Juan Moreno', 11, 22, 'PERSON'), ('Cuenca', 38, 44, 'ORG'), ('Ecuador', 46, 53, 'GPE'), ('the United States', 57, 74, 'GPE'), ('Diane', 141, 146, 'PERSON'), ('Orlando Florida', 168, 183, 'ORG'), ('second', 255, 261, 'ORDINAL'), ('Cuenca', 270, 276, 'ORG'), ('Anna', 310, 314, 'PERSON'), ('120,000', 368, 375, 'MONEY'), ('4', 396, 397, 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 407, 408, 'CARDINAL'), ('Spanish', 450, 457, 'NORP'), ('Monica Rodas', 597, 609, 'PERSON'), ('4', 627, 628, 'CARDINAL'), ('1 1/2', 634, 639, 'CARDINAL'), ('2,798 square feet', 655, 672, 'QUANTITY'), ('135,000', 685, 692, 'MONEY'), ('Diane', 749, 754, 'PERSON'), ('Juan', 759, 763, 'PERSON'), ('Juan', 814, 818, 'PERSON'), ('Monica', 947, 953, 'PERSON'), ('105,000', 1001, 1008, 'MONEY'), ('4', 1025, 1026, 'CARDINAL'), ('3 1/2', 1033, 1038, 'CARDINAL'), ('1,800 square feet', 1052, 1069, 'QUANTITY'), ('third', 1175, 1180, 'ORDINAL'), ('first', 1242, 1247, 'ORDINAL'), ('Monica', 1372, 1378, 'PERSON'), ('85,000', 1418, 1424, 'MONEY'), ('4', 1470, 1471, 'CARDINAL'), ('2 1/2', 1485, 1490, 'CARDINAL'), ('2,000 square feet', 1504, 1521, 'QUANTITY'), ('three', 1706, 1711, 'CARDINAL'), ('Juan', 1755, 1759, 'PERSON')]",Orlando,United States,Cuenca,Ecuador,0,325
"Athos and Mary raised four children in the suburbs of Washington, DC. Now there are five grandchildren in the mix, and beach vacations are what they all enjoy most. Now that Athos and Mary have retired from the restaurant business they're ready to buy a vacation condo so the family can hit the beach together whenever they want. They're focusing their search on the Caribbean nation of the Dominican Republic because they love the beautiful blue waters, crystal clear skies, and affordable prices. The first condo that real estate agent Rico Pester takes them to has 2 bedrooms and 2 1/2 baths in 1720 square feet. It is in a development that is still under construction. Athos loves the breathtaking beachfront views, and Mary loves the in-unit laundry hook-ups. But the condo is priced at $417,000, which is $17,000 over their budget. The other disadvantage is that the development is a significant drive to town. The next place they see is a little closer in. It's a semi-attached villa that is reminiscent of the Greek architecture of Athos's youth. It has a private courtyard with pool and a spectacular rooftop deck. There are 3 bedrooms and 3 baths. Mary loves the extra space, but is disappointed to hear there is no in-unit laundry hook-up. She also finds the kitchen a bit small, but Athos likes the price: $314,000. The third place Rico takes them to is listed for the even more affordable price of $277,000. It has 2 bedrooms and 2 baths in 1500 square feet. It does not have water views, but it is on a golf course, and is just a short ride to the beach by golf cart. Choosing the right place for their family is not going to be easy, but it's definitely worth it to Athos and Mary who are ready to make this dream a reality for themselves, their children, and their grandchildren.",20-Jan-10,S12E07,Multiple Generations of the Hatziyannis Family Hope to Find a Vacation Home in the Dominican Republic,7,12,2010,"[('Mary', 10, 14, 'PERSON'), ('four', 22, 26, 'CARDINAL'), ('Washington, DC', 54, 68, 'GPE'), ('five', 84, 88, 'CARDINAL'), ('Mary', 184, 188, 'PERSON'), ('Caribbean', 367, 376, 'LOC'), ('the Dominican Republic', 387, 409, 'GPE'), ('first', 503, 508, 'ORDINAL'), ('Rico Pester', 538, 549, 'PERSON'), ('2', 568, 569, 'CARDINAL'), ('2 1/2', 583, 588, 'CARDINAL'), ('1720 square feet', 598, 614, 'QUANTITY'), ('Mary', 724, 728, 'PERSON'), ('417,000', 793, 800, 'MONEY'), ('17,000', 812, 818, 'MONEY'), ('Greek', 1018, 1023, 'NORP'), ('Athos', 1040, 1045, 'ORG'), ('3', 1134, 1135, 'CARDINAL'), ('3', 1149, 1150, 'CARDINAL'), ('Mary', 1158, 1162, 'PERSON'), ('314,000', 1319, 1326, 'MONEY'), ('third', 1332, 1337, 'ORDINAL'), ('Rico', 1344, 1348, 'LAW'), ('277,000', 1412, 1419, 'MONEY'), ('2', 1428, 1429, 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 1443, 1444, 'CARDINAL'), ('1500 square feet', 1454, 1470, 'QUANTITY'), ('Mary', 1691, 1695, 'PERSON')]","Washington, DC",United States,,Dominican Republic,1,319
"This busy family of 6 loves their Tucson, Arizona lifestyle, but they yearn for a relaxing Fiji island getaway. Top of their list is a place with plenty of room for themselves and their guests, a large eat-in kitchen, ocean views and a big pool with plenty of outdoor living space. They'd like to stay under their $500,000 budget. The first place their agent Will takes them to see is a 1700 square foot house that's listed for $275,000. It only has 2 bedrooms and 2 bathrooms, and no pool, but it's on almost an acre of land so there is room to expand. The home has breath-taking ocean views, but the kitchen is older and the fridge is tiny. The next house they look at is priced higher, at $325,000, but it's also larger, with 3 bedrooms and 3 bathrooms in 2500 square feet. The best feature of the house is the enormous great room that opens out onto the large deck. Jon loves the pool and outdoor living space but because it's on only ? an acre, Michelle is worried that they wouldn't be able to expand the house in the future. The last house they look at is listed for $450,000 and is made up of 3000 square feet divided among 4 villas. The main villa has a large open kitchen/living/dining space, with a long patio that has a water view. The other three villas are identical, and come with two queen-sized beds, a giant spa tub, and an open shower each. The large pool area comes with a swim-up bar, a separate kiddie pool, a massage table, over-sized patio furniture and a grill. Jon is concerned about the upkeep such a large property would need. After weighing the pros and cons of all 3 properties, Jon and Michelle have reached their decision.",3-Jan-10,S12E01,"This Busy Family of 6 Loves Their Tucson, Arizona Lifestyle, but They Yearn for a Relaxing Vacation Home in Fiji",1,12,2010,"[('6', 20, 21, 'CARDINAL'), ('Tucson', 34, 40, 'GPE'), ('Arizona', 42, 49, 'GPE'), ('Fiji island', 91, 102, 'LOC'), ('500,000', 315, 322, 'MONEY'), ('first', 335, 340, 'ORDINAL'), ('Will', 359, 363, 'PERSON'), ('1700 square foot', 387, 403, 'QUANTITY'), ('275,000', 429, 436, 'MONEY'), ('2', 450, 451, 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 465, 466, 'CARDINAL'), ('almost an acre', 503, 517, 'QUANTITY'), ('325,000', 693, 700, 'MONEY'), ('3', 729, 730, 'CARDINAL'), ('3', 744, 745, 'CARDINAL'), ('2500 square feet', 759, 775, 'QUANTITY'), ('Jon', 870, 873, 'PERSON'), ('Michelle', 950, 958, 'PERSON'), ('450,000', 1075, 1082, 'MONEY'), ('3000 square feet', 1101, 1117, 'QUANTITY'), ('4', 1132, 1133, 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 1254, 1259, 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 1296, 1299, 'CARDINAL'), ('Jon', 1487, 1490, 'PERSON'), ('3', 1595, 1596, 'CARDINAL'), ('Jon', 1609, 1612, 'PERSON'), ('Michelle', 1617, 1625, 'PERSON')]","Tucson, Arizona",United States,,Fiji,1,306
"Dia is from Oklahoma City, Oklahoma but lives onboard a cruise ship for most of the year, working as a singer. Her boyfriend Garo is a sound engineer on the same ship. Their favorite cruises are through the Caribbean, and they've gotten to the point where they want a place of their own in the islands so they can spend even more time there. They've chosen St. Maarten, mostly because of its fun atmosphere. Their budget for a getaway condo is $300,000 and the main thing they are looking for is no renovations. That's because back home in Oklahoma, Dia has been renovating her home for several years and it's the last thing she wants to be doing on vacation too. The first place real estate agent Dwain Carbon shows them is listed for $290,000. It's a one bedroom, one bath condo with a fabulous ocean view. But the development is popular with retirees, and Dia and Garo were hoping for a more youthful vibe. The second place is brand new construction, in fact the units are not even completed. This condo, too, has one bedroom and one bath, but no view. However, the condo complex has a fun, inviting, modern vibe. It's listed for $295,000. The third place is listed for $295,000, and is much larger than the other two. It has three bedrooms and two and a half baths, which would give them plenty of room for company. But the location of the complex is not ideal, as it would mean a significant drive into town or to the beach. Which condo will Dia and Garo choose as their island getaway? Find out, when House Hunters International sails to the Caribbean island of St. Maarten.",18-Jul-10,S14E11,Cruise Ship Employees Want a Condo on Dry Land and Have Chosen the Caribbean Island of St. Maarten.,11,14,2010,"[('Oklahoma City', 12, 25, 'GPE'), ('Oklahoma', 27, 35, 'GPE'), ('most of the year', 72, 88, 'DATE'), ('Garo', 125, 129, 'PERSON'), ('Caribbean', 207, 216, 'LOC'), ('St. Maarten', 357, 368, 'PERSON'), ('300,000', 445, 452, 'MONEY'), ('Oklahoma', 540, 548, 'GPE'), ('Dia', 550, 553, 'GPE'), ('several years', 587, 600, 'DATE'), ('first', 668, 673, 'ORDINAL'), ('Dwain Carbon', 698, 710, 'PERSON'), ('290,000', 737, 744, 'MONEY'), ('one', 753, 756, 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 766, 769, 'CARDINAL'), ('Dia and Garo', 859, 871, 'PERSON'), ('second', 914, 920, 'ORDINAL'), ('one', 1017, 1020, 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 1033, 1036, 'CARDINAL'), ('295,000', 1134, 1141, 'MONEY'), ('third', 1147, 1152, 'ORDINAL'), ('295,000', 1174, 1181, 'MONEY'), ('two', 1217, 1220, 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 1229, 1234, 'CARDINAL'), ('two and a half', 1248, 1262, 'CARDINAL'), ('Dia', 1447, 1450, 'PERSON'), ('Garo', 1455, 1459, 'PERSON'), ('House Hunters International', 1507, 1534, 'ORG'), ('Caribbean', 1548, 1557, 'LOC'), ('St. Maarten', 1568, 1579, 'EVENT')]",Oklahoma City,United States,St. Maarten,Netherlands,0,287
"In the nine years Adam Graves and his wife Allison have been married, they have relocated for his career to Kansas City, Phoenix, Los Angeles, and Cleveland. Moving that many times would be hard on any family but with two young girls, ages three and 18 months, it's made things even more stressful. After their latest move to Cleveland, it seemed as though they were going to finally be able to settle down. They bought their dream house and planned to raise their kids Madison and Morgan in Ohio, but only ten months into living there, Adam was offered another promotion. He was given the chance to become a brand manager at his company's headquarters, which unfortunately for his travel weary family, was in Vevey, Switzerland. Recognizing this was an opportunity of a lifetime, Allison once again agreed to support her husband's career and give the home of Lake Geneva a try. Having lived internationally before, Adam is comfortable acclimating to a new culture, but trying to navigate the ins and outs of being a stay at home mom, in a foreign country, may be a harder adjustment for Allison. She knows if she can find a place that has the size and amenities of her homes in the U.S., it can help smooth the transition. Places that fit that bill however, are outside the city center and with Adam's desire for a short commute to his downtown office also a top priority, real estate agent Pamela Giuffrida is going to have a tough time delivering, even with their seemingly high $5,000 a month budget. Watch as the Graves stir things up again, when House Hunters International visits the Swiss city of Vevey.		",23-Jan-14,S62E01,"On the road again to Vevey, Switzerland",1,62,2014,"[('the nine years', 3, 17, 'DATE'), ('Adam Graves', 18, 29, 'PERSON'), ('Allison', 43, 50, 'PERSON'), ('Kansas City', 108, 119, 'GPE'), ('Phoenix', 121, 128, 'GPE'), ('Los Angeles', 130, 141, 'GPE'), ('Cleveland', 147, 156, 'GPE'), ('two', 218, 221, 'CARDINAL'), ('three and 18 months', 240, 259, 'DATE'), ('Cleveland', 326, 335, 'GPE'), ('Madison', 470, 477, 'PERSON'), ('Morgan', 482, 488, 'PERSON'), ('Ohio', 492, 496, 'GPE'), ('only ten months', 502, 517, 'DATE'), ('Adam', 537, 541, 'PERSON'), ('Vevey', 710, 715, 'GPE'), ('Switzerland', 717, 728, 'GPE'), ('Allison', 781, 788, 'ORG'), ('Lake Geneva', 860, 871, 'FAC'), ('Adam', 916, 920, 'PERSON'), ('Allison', 1088, 1095, 'PERSON'), ('U.S.', 1183, 1187, 'GPE'), ('Adam', 1296, 1300, 'PERSON'), ('Pamela Giuffrida', 1392, 1408, 'PERSON'), ('5,000', 1483, 1488, 'MONEY'), ('House Hunters International', 1552, 1579, 'ORG'), ('Swiss', 1591, 1596, 'NORP'), ('Vevey', 1605, 1610, 'GPE')]",Cleveland,United States,Vevey,Switzerland,0,283
"Native South Carolinians McKinley and Natalie have lived in their hometown of Columbia their whole lives. Married for several years now and the parents of four little children, they feel it is time to branch out and explore parts of the world outside of their southern comfort zone. After a vacation in Belize they realized it would be the perfect place to move their family. The children are still young and therefore very flexible and both parents want them to experience a different culture, a change in landscape and grow up in a place where outside activity supersedes sitting in front of a television or video game station. Mom and Dad are outdoor enthusiasts as well so they also look forward to the outdoor activities available in Belize year-round. In order to finance the move, builder McKinley recently sold his construction business and plans to get into real estate sales in Belize once relocated. Looking to start off renting as they investigate the housing market, the couple's budget cannot exceed 5500 dollars and McKinley is adamant about that. Seeing as they need a house big enough for a family of six and both want to be close to amenities such as the beach, pools and tennis this might be a challenge for real estate agent Macarena. But she knows her stuff and will try her best to get this active family settled into a home and location that works for everyone. Will she succeed? Will McKinley and Natalie regret the move or embrace the tropical adventure they are so ready for? Find out when House Hunters International takes a long hike to Belize.",27-Apr-12,S36E03,Family of Six in Belize,3,36,2012,"[('Native South Carolinians', 0, 24, 'ORG'), ('McKinley', 25, 33, 'PERSON'), ('Natalie', 38, 45, 'PERSON'), ('Columbia', 78, 86, 'ORG'), ('several years', 118, 131, 'DATE'), ('four', 155, 159, 'CARDINAL'), ('Belize', 303, 309, 'GPE'), ('Dad', 638, 641, 'PERSON'), ('Belize', 739, 745, 'GPE'), ('McKinley', 796, 804, 'PERSON'), ('Belize', 888, 894, 'GPE'), ('5500 dollars', 1014, 1026, 'MONEY'), ('McKinley', 1031, 1039, 'ORG'), ('six', 1118, 1121, 'CARDINAL'), ('Macarena', 1245, 1253, 'PERSON'), ('Will McKinley', 1403, 1416, 'PERSON'), ('Natalie', 1421, 1428, 'PERSON'), ('House Hunters International', 1516, 1543, 'ORG'), ('Belize', 1565, 1571, 'GPE')]","Columbia, South Carolina",United States,,Belize,1,273
"Ruth and Todd Richert love almost everything about their native Calgary. They met there, have family there, and its proximity to tons of outdoor activities made it a great place to call home. But, when the point came where the comforts of Canada were too safe of a bet for these thrill seekers, they started to look at ways to shake things up. Todd, a high school math teacher, started to explore how he could do what he loves in a different setting, so when an opportunity to teach in an English language school in Bangkok came up, they both decided this was the change they were looking for. Ruth recently graduated with her Master's degree and won't have a job immediately, so finding a way to occupy her time in Thailand is her priority one. She wants to be in the heart of the action so she can easily explore the city and have plenty to do. Todd would rather live outside central Bangkok in the more relaxed suburbs, which also has the added benefit of being where his school is. Having decidedly different perspectives over where to live is only one of the challenges real estate agent Patricia Lee will have to contend with, as she tries to find them a spacious, two-bedroom apartment on their $700 a month budget. Watch as Ruth and Todd decide whether simple and serene is more appealing than a new experience in a lively location, as House Hunters International explores Bangkok, Thailand.",23-Jan-14,S62E11,"Location Lessons in Bangkok, Thailand",11,62,2014,"[('Ruth', 0, 4, 'PERSON'), ('Todd Richert', 9, 21, 'PERSON'), ('Calgary', 64, 71, 'GPE'), ('tons', 129, 133, 'QUANTITY'), ('Canada', 239, 245, 'GPE'), ('Todd', 344, 348, 'PERSON'), ('English', 489, 496, 'LANGUAGE'), ('Bangkok', 516, 523, 'GPE'), ('Ruth', 594, 598, 'PERSON'), ('Thailand', 716, 724, 'GPE'), ('Todd', 847, 851, 'PERSON'), ('Bangkok', 886, 893, 'GPE'), ('Patricia Lee', 1093, 1105, 'PERSON'), ('two', 1171, 1174, 'CARDINAL'), ('700', 1203, 1206, 'MONEY'), ('Ruth', 1232, 1236, 'PERSON'), ('Todd', 1241, 1245, 'PERSON'), ('House Hunters International', 1344, 1371, 'ORG'), ('Bangkok', 1381, 1388, 'GPE'), ('Thailand', 1390, 1398, 'GPE')]",Calgary,Canada,Bangkok,Thailand,0,250
"Bruce Chipps leads a stressful life in Los Angeles, California, directing a live, four-hour television broadcast from area race tracks. But the job comes with one fabulous perk: Bruce gets up to six months off each year. Recently, Bruce saw the movie ""Under the Tuscan Sun"" which tells the story of an American woman who moves to the Italian countryside to renovate a centuries-old home, and live ""the sweet life."" Bruce was inspired and decided he wanted to do the same thing during his ample vacation time each year. He has just $65,000 to spend, so instead of Tuscany, which is known to be expensive, Bruce plans to look for a villa in the nearby region of Abruzzo. Helping Bruce realize his dream is real estate agent Nicola Anne Di Girolamo. The first place she shows Bruce is listed right on budget, at $65,000, and has 1300 square feet. The downstairs is in good shape, but the upstairs requires a total renovation. The second place is not at all renovated, and would require serious work to make it even livable. But it's listed at just $26,000, and has 800 square feet. The third place is just the opposite. It is completely renovated with style and has 1300 square feet, but it's listed at a budget breaking $143,000. Is Bruce willing to spend more? Or is he happy to take on significant overseas renovations? Find out when House Hunters International travels to the Italian countryside.",2-May-10,S13E09,"Bruce Hopes to Find a Villa in the Italian Countryside for Less Than $65,000.",9,13,2010,"[('Bruce Chipps', 0, 12, 'PERSON'), ('Los Angeles', 39, 50, 'GPE'), ('California', 52, 62, 'GPE'), ('four-hour', 82, 91, 'TIME'), ('one', 159, 162, 'CARDINAL'), ('up to six months off each year', 189, 219, 'DATE'), ('Bruce', 231, 236, 'PERSON'), ('Under the Tuscan Sun', 252, 272, 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('American', 302, 310, 'NORP'), ('Italian', 334, 341, 'NORP'), ('centuries-old', 368, 381, 'DATE'), ('Bruce', 415, 420, 'PERSON'), ('each year', 508, 517, 'DATE'), ('just $65,000', 526, 538, 'MONEY'), ('Bruce', 604, 609, 'ORG'), ('Helping Bruce', 669, 682, 'PERSON'), ('Nicola Anne Di Girolamo', 722, 745, 'PERSON'), ('first', 751, 756, 'ORDINAL'), ('Bruce', 773, 778, 'PERSON'), ('65,000', 810, 816, 'MONEY'), ('1300 square feet', 826, 842, 'QUANTITY'), ('second', 927, 933, 'ORDINAL'), ('just $26,000', 1040, 1052, 'MONEY'), ('800 square feet', 1062, 1077, 'QUANTITY'), ('third', 1083, 1088, 'ORDINAL'), ('1300 square feet', 1163, 1179, 'QUANTITY'), ('143,000', 1219, 1226, 'MONEY'), ('Bruce', 1231, 1236, 'PERSON'), ('House Hunters International', 1334, 1361, 'ORG'), ('Italian', 1377, 1384, 'NORP')]",Los Angeles,United States,Abruzzo,Italy,0,244
"California residents Jesse and Kelly love spending time at the beach in their Santa Barbara area. The active couple is especially fond of soaking up the sun and surfing the waves. When they got married they went on their honeymoon to San Juan Del Sur, a premier surf destination in Nicaragua known for its pristine beaches and amazing waves. They fell so in love with the coastal region that they've decided to buy a vacation home there. They're hoping to find a home that's near a surf beach and ideally falls within their $150,000 to $200,000 budget. Helping them find a home is their close personal friend and realtor, Brooke Rundle. The first place their pal shows them is a 900 square foot studio with amazing beach views and is listed for $185,000. The condo property is adjacent to a hotel that allows homeowners access to its restaurant and pool area. The second option is a 1600 square foot, two bedroom villa in a gated community that is listed for $200,000. Like the first property, this one is also near a hotel that allows homeowners access to its pool and restaurant. The final home they look at is two story home listed for $175,000. The 1500 square foot property has two bedrooms and is located right at a surf spot with fantastic views. Jesse and Kelly are just one decision away from a surf side vacation paradise in Nicaragua.",13-Jun-10,S14E01,California Surfer Couple Looks for a Beach Side Vacation Home in Nicaragua,1,14,2010,"[('California', 0, 10, 'GPE'), ('Jesse', 21, 26, 'PERSON'), ('Kelly', 31, 36, 'PERSON'), ('Santa Barbara', 78, 91, 'GPE'), ('San Juan Del Sur', 234, 250, 'GPE'), ('Nicaragua', 282, 291, 'GPE'), ('$150,000 to $200,000', 524, 544, 'MONEY'), ('Brooke Rundle', 622, 635, 'PERSON'), ('first', 641, 646, 'ORDINAL'), ('900 square foot', 679, 694, 'QUANTITY'), ('185,000', 746, 753, 'MONEY'), ('second', 864, 870, 'ORDINAL'), ('1600 square foot', 883, 899, 'QUANTITY'), ('two', 901, 904, 'CARDINAL'), ('200,000', 960, 967, 'MONEY'), ('first', 978, 983, 'ORDINAL'), ('two', 1113, 1116, 'CARDINAL'), ('175,000', 1140, 1147, 'MONEY'), ('1500 square foot', 1153, 1169, 'QUANTITY'), ('two', 1183, 1186, 'CARDINAL'), ('Jesse', 1254, 1259, 'PERSON'), ('Kelly', 1264, 1269, 'PERSON'), ('one', 1279, 1282, 'CARDINAL'), ('Nicaragua', 1335, 1344, 'GPE')]",Santa Barbara,United States,San Juan Del Sur,Nicaragua,0,239
"Darrell and Frankie are an engaged couple that live in the Marietta, Georgia area. Each of them has children who have grown up and gone off to school or work, so now it's just the two of them. Darrell works long hours while Frankie deals with a hectic commute to the office, so they'd like to have a place where they can get away and relax. They chose Costa Rica as the location for their vacation home after the couple went there on a trip and fell in love with a small, tranquil area called Playa Samara. They're looking for a low maintenance home with a large kitchen that is located near the beach. Darrell would also like to be sure that he is looking at places that are desirable to the locals that fall within their $600,000 budget because the home is also an investment property. Their real estate agent, Ryan Tuttle will show them the wide range of properties they can choose from in Costa Rica. They check out a 2 bedroom townhome with amazing views listed for $595,000 and then head to a smaller 2 bedroom condo with great beach views that is listed at $330,000 and finally they'll tour a 3 bedroom house that also has a great view of the beach and is listed for $449,000. Which of the three homes will Darrell and Frankie choose to be their new vacation retreat?",14-Apr-10,S13E04,Georgia Couple Looking to Escape Their Busy Lives Search for a Vacation Home in Costa Rica (Vacation Retreat in Costa Rica),4,13,2010,"[('Marietta', 59, 67, 'FAC'), ('Georgia', 69, 76, 'GPE'), ('two', 180, 183, 'CARDINAL'), ('long hours', 207, 217, 'TIME'), ('Costa Rica', 352, 362, 'GPE'), ('Playa', 493, 498, 'ORG'), ('Darrell', 603, 610, 'ORG'), ('600,000', 724, 731, 'MONEY'), ('Ryan Tuttle', 813, 824, 'PERSON'), ('Costa Rica', 893, 903, 'GPE'), ('2', 922, 923, 'CARDINAL'), ('595,000', 972, 979, 'MONEY'), ('2', 1007, 1008, 'CARDINAL'), ('great beach', 1028, 1039, 'FAC'), ('330,000', 1065, 1072, 'MONEY'), ('3', 1100, 1101, 'CARDINAL'), ('449,000', 1175, 1182, 'MONEY'), ('three', 1197, 1202, 'CARDINAL'), ('Darrell', 1214, 1221, 'PERSON'), ('Frankie', 1226, 1233, 'PERSON')]",Marietta,United States,Playa Samara,Costa Rica,0,237
"Nick Dray and Nikki Alexander met at a surf club in their native city of Sydney, Australia. What started out as a friendship has grown into a six year relationship. Though they love the sea and are beach kids at heart, they feel it's time to switch up the scenery and move to London, England which they plan on using as a launch-pad for exploring Europe. They have many friends and a couple of family members already living in London so though they will be very far from home, they will not be alone. Moving to a foreign city without jobs or a permanent place to live is a bit risky but they're young and adventurous and feel confident that everything will fall into place. Their main concern actually, is the weather. Saying goodbye to the sun, sand and surf will be hard and they're just hoping to find a home in the city with some outdoor space so that they have a little breathing room. Nick and Nikki are eager to begin their new journey and look forward to exploring all of Europe from their new home-base in London. What they are probably not prepared for is the tricky and competitive real estate market. London is one of the most expensive cities in the world and they are in for a real surprise when it comes to how little space you get for your money.",13-Oct-11,S27E07,Longtime Partners Relocate to London,7,27,2011,"[('Nick Dray', 0, 9, 'PERSON'), ('Nikki', 14, 19, 'ORG'), ('Alexander', 20, 29, 'PERSON'), ('Sydney', 73, 79, 'GPE'), ('Australia', 81, 90, 'GPE'), ('a six year', 140, 150, 'DATE'), ('London', 276, 282, 'GPE'), ('England', 284, 291, 'GPE'), ('Europe', 347, 353, 'LOC'), ('London', 427, 433, 'GPE'), ('Nick', 891, 895, 'PERSON'), ('Nikki', 900, 905, 'ORG'), ('Europe', 980, 986, 'LOC'), ('London', 1015, 1021, 'GPE'), ('London', 1113, 1119, 'GPE'), ('one', 1123, 1126, 'CARDINAL')]",Sydney,Australia,London,England,0,236
"Mark and Mary McElroy have a very busy life for themselves in Dallas, Texas. Mark is a President and CEO of a successful technology company, while Mary manages a vibrant household with their four children. Whenever the pressures of handling all their responsibilities gets to be too much, escaping to the pink sand beaches of the Bahamas for vacation, is their go to solution. Mark and Mary are willing to deal with the fast pace until the time comes to retire, but after that, they have decided to spend their well-earned golden years on the island of Eleuthera. Even though they are a few years off from retiring, the McElroy's are feeling an enormous pressure to get a home now. With a land area roughly a hundred miles long and a mile wide, beachfront real estate is at a premium and as more people have caught wind of its secluded beauty, the competition to join Mark and Mary is getting more intense. Mary is willing to fix any space up as long as she is beachfront, but Mark is looking to keep costs down around their million-dollar budget. Will Mary's creative eye make Mark only see the dollar signs or will the here today, gone tomorrow housing market pass them by before they even have a chance to decide? Watch as House Hunters International tries to live the good life on the Bahamian island of Eleuthera.",30-Jun-13,S54E08,"Retiring off to Eleuthera, Bahamas",8,54,2013,"[('Mark', 0, 4, 'PERSON'), ('Mary McElroy', 9, 21, 'PERSON'), ('Dallas', 62, 68, 'GPE'), ('Texas', 70, 75, 'GPE'), ('Mark', 77, 81, 'PERSON'), ('Mary', 147, 151, 'PERSON'), ('four', 191, 195, 'CARDINAL'), ('Bahamas', 330, 337, 'GPE'), ('Mark', 377, 381, 'PERSON'), ('Mary', 386, 390, 'PERSON'), ('Eleuthera', 553, 562, 'ORG'), ('a few years', 585, 596, 'DATE'), ('McElroy', 620, 627, 'ORG'), ('roughly a hundred miles', 699, 722, 'QUANTITY'), ('a mile', 732, 738, 'QUANTITY'), ('Mark', 868, 872, 'PERSON'), ('Mary', 877, 881, 'PERSON'), ('Mary', 907, 911, 'PERSON'), ('Mark', 977, 981, 'PERSON'), ('million-dollar', 1025, 1039, 'MONEY'), (""Will Mary's"", 1048, 1059, 'PERSON'), ('Mark', 1078, 1082, 'PERSON'), ('today', 1126, 1131, 'DATE'), ('tomorrow', 1138, 1146, 'DATE'), ('House Hunters International', 1226, 1253, 'ORG'), ('the Bahamian island', 1285, 1304, 'LOC'), ('Eleuthera', 1308, 1317, 'ORG')]",Dallas,United States,Eleuthera,The Bahamas,0,236
"Jeff and Tamara Katko love the life they've built for their family of four in comfortable Perrysburg, Ohio. There's only one thing missing; wintertime sunshine. For that, they're heading to the U.S. Virgin Islands in search of a vacation home that's sure to deliver. They'd like a two or three bedroom, two bathroom condo that's fully furnished, with a nice patio or deck, and that is within walking distance to a beach. If they could score an actual water view, they'd be delighted. Their budget is $350,000 - $450,000, which actually won't go a very long way in St. Croix, so this could be tough. Sales Associate Kerry Waldo is ready for the challenge. The first place she shows them is listed for $379,000. It has three bedrooms and two large decks, but is far from the beach. The second condo, listed at $460,000, is just steps from the sand, but only has two bedrooms, which means the Katko boys would have to share a room. The third condo also has just two bedrooms, and it's not close to the beach, but it's part of a lush golf course resort, and is listed for the more comfortable price of $350,000. What are Jeff and Tamara willing to compromise on? Walking distance to the beach? A third bedroom? Or price? Find out as House Hunters International travels to tropical St. Croix in the U.S. Virgin Islands.",7-Apr-10,S13E06,"Ohioans Jeff and Tamara Katko Honeymooned in the U.S. Virgin Islands, and Now Want a Vacation Home There That the Whole Family Can Enjoy (Ohioans Head Back to St. Croix)",6,13,2010,"[('Jeff', 0, 4, 'PERSON'), ('Tamara Katko', 9, 21, 'PERSON'), ('four', 70, 74, 'CARDINAL'), ('Perrysburg', 90, 100, 'GPE'), ('Ohio', 102, 106, 'GPE'), ('only one', 116, 124, 'CARDINAL'), ('the U.S. Virgin Islands', 190, 213, 'GPE'), ('two', 281, 284, 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 288, 293, 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 303, 306, 'CARDINAL'), ('350,000', 501, 508, 'MONEY'), ('450,000', 512, 519, 'MONEY'), ('St. Croix', 564, 573, 'GPE'), ('Kerry Waldo', 615, 626, 'PERSON'), ('first', 659, 664, 'ORDINAL'), ('379,000', 701, 708, 'MONEY'), ('three', 717, 722, 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 736, 739, 'QUANTITY'), ('second', 784, 790, 'ORDINAL'), ('460,000', 809, 816, 'MONEY'), ('two', 860, 863, 'CARDINAL'), ('Katko', 890, 895, 'GPE'), ('third', 933, 938, 'ORDINAL'), ('two', 959, 962, 'CARDINAL'), ('350,000', 1099, 1106, 'MONEY'), ('Jeff', 1117, 1121, 'PERSON'), ('Tamara', 1126, 1132, 'PERSON'), ('third', 1192, 1197, 'ORDINAL'), ('House Hunters International', 1229, 1256, 'ORG'), ('St. Croix', 1277, 1286, 'GPE'), ('the U.S. Virgin Islands', 1290, 1313, 'GPE')]",Perrysburg,United States,St. Croix,United States,0,235
"Raising their kids on the island of Sicily is a dream come true for ex-Londoners, Jon and Reeva. But squeezing their three children and their home-based travel business into a small three-bedroom rental house is growing on their nerves. They're ready to buy a spacious home of their own on this historic Mediterranean island. They're open to remodeling, and their budget is $730,000 US. Real estate agent Frank Riela has learned to navigate the island's somewhat antiquated real estate practices, and believes he can help Jon and Reeva find the perfect home for their family and business. The first house he shows them has three bedrooms and the potential for a second level, sea-view master suite. But Jon doesn't like the home's close proximity to the neighbors. It's listed for 476,000 US. The next place Frank shows them has five bedrooms, but they are spread across three separate buildings, which means that Jon and Reeva's oldest two children, Francesca and Mia, will be sleeping in a separate structure, and Mia's not happy about that. Also, it's listed for a budget-topping $724,000. The final place Frank shows Jon and Reeva is a total fixer. But it has the potential for 3,800 square feet and is priced at only $361,000 US. Just how much renovation are Jon and Reeva willing to take on? Find out when House Hunters International travels to Sicily, Italy.",20-Jun-10,S14E09,"Jon and Reeva Hope to Find a Spacious, Historic Home on the Island of Sicily for Their Growing Family (Brits Buy in Sicily)",9,14,2010,"[('Sicily', 36, 42, 'GPE'), ('Jon', 82, 85, 'PERSON'), ('Reeva', 90, 95, 'PERSON'), ('three', 117, 122, 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 182, 187, 'CARDINAL'), ('Mediterranean island', 304, 324, 'LOC'), ('730,000', 375, 382, 'MONEY'), ('US', 383, 385, 'GPE'), ('Frank Riela', 405, 416, 'PERSON'), ('Jon', 522, 525, 'PERSON'), ('Reeva', 530, 535, 'PERSON'), ('first', 593, 598, 'ORDINAL'), ('three', 623, 628, 'CARDINAL'), ('second', 662, 668, 'ORDINAL'), ('Jon', 703, 706, 'PERSON'), ('476,000', 781, 788, 'CARDINAL'), ('US', 789, 791, 'GPE'), ('Frank', 808, 813, 'PERSON'), ('five', 829, 833, 'CARDINAL'), ('three', 871, 876, 'CARDINAL'), ('Jon', 914, 917, 'PERSON'), ('Reeva', 922, 927, 'PERSON'), ('two', 937, 940, 'CARDINAL'), ('Francesca', 951, 960, 'PERSON'), ('Mia', 965, 968, 'PERSON'), ('Mia', 1016, 1019, 'PERSON'), ('724,000', 1084, 1091, 'MONEY'), ('Frank', 1109, 1114, 'PERSON'), ('Jon', 1121, 1124, 'PERSON'), ('Reeva', 1129, 1134, 'PERSON'), ('3,800 square feet', 1182, 1199, 'QUANTITY'), ('only $361,000', 1217, 1230, 'MONEY'), ('US', 1231, 1233, 'GPE'), ('Jon', 1264, 1267, 'PERSON'), ('Reeva', 1272, 1277, 'PERSON'), ('House Hunters International', 1312, 1339, 'ORG'), ('Sicily', 1351, 1357, 'GPE'), ('Italy', 1359, 1364, 'GPE')]",London,England,Sicily,Italy,0,231
"David, a graphic designer, and his fiance Charlie have been living a fast-paced, busy life in London for years. Now that they have a 7 month old daughter, Layla, they've decided to trade in city living for a more peaceful life on the beaches of Costa da Caparica, Portugal. They chose this area because David is of Portuguese heritage and has cherished childhood memories of playing on these beaches as a kid on holiday with his family. He wants nothing more than his little girl to grow up with the same memories and knows that raising her on the beach will benefit the entire family. Costa da Caparica is only 20 minutes outside of Lisbon so they're both hoping to reignite their careers in the city while enjoying seaside living. David, who can work from home, is especially hopeful that he'll find his dream house on the beach. Given their limited budget however, finding space to live, work and provide a room for Layla may be a challenge. Real estate agent Ronald Wayne, a British ex-pat himself, wants to get the young family settled in a home in what he describes as one of the best places to live in the world. Will they get the beachfront property they're after or will budget issues send them inland? Find out when House Hunters International heads to Costa da Caparica, Portugal.",27-Feb-12,S31E08,Native Londoner returns to his Portugal roots,8,31,2012,"[('David', 0, 5, 'PERSON'), ('Charlie', 42, 49, 'PERSON'), ('London', 94, 100, 'GPE'), ('years', 105, 110, 'DATE'), ('7 month old', 133, 144, 'DATE'), ('Layla', 155, 160, 'PERSON'), ('Costa da Caparica', 245, 262, 'GPE'), ('Portugal', 264, 272, 'GPE'), ('David', 303, 308, 'PERSON'), ('Portuguese', 315, 325, 'NORP'), ('Costa da Caparica', 586, 603, 'GPE'), ('20 minutes', 612, 622, 'TIME'), ('Lisbon', 634, 640, 'GPE'), ('David', 733, 738, 'PERSON'), ('Layla', 919, 924, 'PERSON'), ('Ronald Wayne', 963, 975, 'PERSON'), ('British', 979, 986, 'NORP'), ('House Hunters International', 1226, 1253, 'ORG'), ('Costa da Caparica', 1263, 1280, 'GPE'), ('Portugal', 1282, 1290, 'GPE')]",London,England,Costa da Caparica,Portugal,0,229
"Because of his father's job, Jeff Coltharp has never been grounded to any place for longer than a couple of years and this fostered a love of traveling that has carried through to his adult life. Jeff was able to parlay this into a career where he could traverse the globe teaching English. It was on one of his stops to Ukraine where he met Katya, and being the first English speaker she spoke to, they quickly formed a bond and now are happily married. Katya is ready to spread her wings and Jeff is excited for her try something new so the couple have chosen to move to Krakow, Poland. Where they differ however is in how they will live once they get there - Jeff is more free-spirited and as long as there is room to teach in, he can justify almost any type of living situation. Katya on the other hand, is more practical and has a clear vision of wanting to live in an updated surrounding. Finding modernity and space, together in the coveted Old Town district is rare, so if they want to land a place there, they may need to be willing to stretch their $600 a month budget. Find out when House Hunters International tries to settle in the Royal Capital City of Krakow, Poland.",11-Oct-12,S43E06,"Blazing a New Trail in Krakow, Poland",6,43,2012,"[('Jeff Coltharp', 29, 42, 'PERSON'), ('a couple of years', 96, 113, 'DATE'), ('Jeff', 196, 200, 'PERSON'), ('English', 282, 289, 'LANGUAGE'), ('Ukraine', 321, 328, 'GPE'), ('Katya', 342, 347, 'PERSON'), ('first', 363, 368, 'ORDINAL'), ('English', 369, 376, 'LANGUAGE'), ('Jeff', 494, 498, 'PERSON'), ('Krakow', 573, 579, 'GPE'), ('Poland', 581, 587, 'GPE'), ('Jeff', 662, 666, 'PERSON'), ('Old Town', 948, 956, 'FAC'), ('600', 1060, 1063, 'MONEY'), ('House Hunters International', 1094, 1121, 'ORG'), ('the Royal Capital City', 1141, 1163, 'FAC'), ('Krakow', 1167, 1173, 'GPE'), ('Poland', 1175, 1181, 'GPE')]",,Ukraine,Krakow,Poland,1,222
"Newlyweds Kurtis and Kathleen Badger have plans to leave the Big Apple for Big Ben. Kurtis is ready to give up his steady sales job for a chance to study law in England. As a lifelong New York resident, Kathleen is willing to leave her hometown so Kurtis can pursue his dream. She's already gotten a job with an accounting firm in London and feels the city's hustle and bustle will make for an easy transition. The only problem is that his school is far out in the country, and the long hours they both will be putting in is creating friction over which location is a better place to find a home. If they stay in the city for Kathleen, small flats and big prices are waiting for them. If they venture out to the country for Kurtis, they'll get more bang for their buck, but the added cost of the commuter trains into central London could raise their monthly outlay to as much as living in the city center. With only Kathleen's income to pull from, Richard Blanco has a tall order finding a property anywhere that will work for their $1,900 a month budget. Find out if it will be close to school or close to work as House Hunters International comes to a verdict in London, England.",9-Nov-13,S56E10,"Commuting Conundrum in London, England",10,56,2013,"[('Newlyweds Kurtis', 0, 16, 'PERSON'), ('Kathleen Badger', 21, 36, 'PERSON'), ('Ben', 79, 82, 'PERSON'), ('Kurtis', 84, 90, 'PERSON'), ('England', 161, 168, 'GPE'), ('New York', 184, 192, 'GPE'), ('Kathleen', 203, 211, 'PERSON'), ('Kurtis', 248, 254, 'GPE'), ('London', 331, 337, 'GPE'), ('the long hours', 478, 492, 'TIME'), ('Kathleen', 626, 634, 'PERSON'), ('Kurtis', 724, 730, 'GPE'), ('London', 825, 831, 'GPE'), ('monthly', 850, 857, 'DATE'), ('Kathleen', 916, 924, 'PERSON'), ('Richard Blanco', 948, 962, 'PERSON'), ('1,900', 1034, 1039, 'MONEY'), ('House Hunters International', 1115, 1142, 'ORG'), ('London', 1165, 1171, 'GPE'), ('England', 1173, 1180, 'GPE')]","New York, New York",United States,London,England,0,221
"Todd and Karin Smith have carved out a comfortable life for their family of four in Clear Lake, Minnesota. They enjoy taking their two boys outdoors and spending time with their tight knit extended family. Karin was content with the way things were but Todd's job transfer to Brussels, Belgium is turning her world upside down. Karin likes her American creature comforts and is reluctant to give them up. Todd sees this as an opportunity to not only advance his career but also broaden his family's horizons. He wants to experience everything the city has to offer, from its world-renowned chocolate and beer, to its historic architecture. One thing they can agree on, Brussels' notoriously congested traffic is something that has them both worried. Karin will have to take the boys to and from school, while Todd will have to drive to work, so they're both pushing hard to find a home that would cut down their commute. With the school and the office on opposite ends of town, real estate agent Steve Hubert will have a difficult time finding not only an ideal location, but also an affordable house that could ease Karin's transition to life in Belgium. Which location will win in the end, as House Hunters International gets a taste of Brussels, Belgium?",1-Aug-13,S55E09,Being Belgian in Brussels,9,55,2013,"[('Todd', 0, 4, 'ORG'), ('Karin Smith', 9, 20, 'PERSON'), ('four', 76, 80, 'CARDINAL'), ('Clear Lake', 84, 94, 'LOC'), ('Minnesota', 96, 105, 'GPE'), ('two', 131, 134, 'CARDINAL'), ('Karin', 206, 211, 'PERSON'), ('Todd', 253, 257, 'PERSON'), ('Brussels', 276, 284, 'GPE'), ('Belgium', 286, 293, 'GPE'), ('Karin', 328, 333, 'GPE'), ('American', 344, 352, 'NORP'), ('Todd', 405, 409, 'PERSON'), ('One', 640, 643, 'CARDINAL'), ('Brussels', 669, 677, 'GPE'), ('Karin', 750, 755, 'PERSON'), ('Todd', 809, 813, 'PERSON'), ('Steve Hubert', 996, 1008, 'PERSON'), ('Karin', 1117, 1122, 'GPE'), ('Belgium', 1147, 1154, 'GPE'), ('House Hunters International', 1195, 1222, 'ORG'), ('Brussels', 1239, 1247, 'GPE'), ('Belgium', 1249, 1256, 'GPE')]","Clear Lake, Minnesota",United States,Brussels,Belgium,0,216
"Beth Morehart knew that when her newlywed husband Tyler enlisted in the Coast Guard, it would have an impact on their family. With Tyler gone for weeks at a time at sea, Beth has grown weary of their long stretches apart. Not only is she missing time with Tyler, but he is also away from their one-year-old daughter, Alaina. So when an opportunity came to get off the boat and into the office, Beth pushed him to seize the chance. The assignment is a win-win for Beth, because not only does she get to spend more time with her husband, but their whole family gets to do it basking in the sun of picturesque Puerto Rico. The problem however, is Tyler and Beth have never really shared the same space since saying, I do, so they're going to have to learn about their new surroundings while figuring each other out. Fortunately, they have help finding a house at their $1,800 a month budget from real estate agent Raquel Esquenazi. The thing Raquel may not be able to assist with is helping Beth and Tyler adjust to life under the same roof. Watch as the Moreharts try to learn about themselves and the rich ports of San Juan when House Hunters International travels to Puerto Rico.",21-Feb-13,S50E03,"Coming Ashore in San Juan, Puerto Rico",3,50,2013,"[('Beth Morehart', 0, 13, 'PERSON'), ('Tyler', 50, 55, 'PERSON'), ('the Coast Guard', 68, 83, 'ORG'), ('Tyler', 131, 136, 'PERSON'), ('weeks', 146, 151, 'DATE'), ('Beth', 170, 174, 'PERSON'), ('Tyler', 256, 261, 'PERSON'), ('one-year-old', 294, 306, 'DATE'), ('Alaina', 317, 323, 'PERSON'), ('Beth', 394, 398, 'PERSON'), ('Beth', 463, 467, 'PERSON'), ('Puerto Rico', 607, 618, 'GPE'), ('Tyler', 644, 649, 'PERSON'), ('Beth', 654, 658, 'PERSON'), ('1,800', 867, 872, 'MONEY'), ('Raquel Esquenazi', 911, 927, 'PERSON'), ('Raquel', 939, 945, 'PERSON'), ('Beth', 988, 992, 'PERSON'), ('Tyler', 997, 1002, 'PERSON'), ('San Juan', 1114, 1122, 'GPE'), ('House Hunters International', 1128, 1155, 'ORG'), ('Puerto Rico', 1167, 1178, 'GPE')]",,,San Juan,Puerto Rico,2,215
"For almost fifteen years, Esther Ndichu has called Atlanta home. From her friends to the weather, she has loved everything about her time in Georgia, but as of late it feels like something has been missing. Her older sister Jennifer lives in England with her two kids and the distance apart is making Esther rethink where she wants to be. So when an opportunity to become a logistics manager in Brussels came up within her company, Esther jumped at the chance to not only give her career a boost but also to be closer to Jennifer. Being in Belgium will make it easier for Jennifer to come and visit her sister, so Esther is hoping to find an apartment that can easily host her family's visits. But, considering Esther is single and her sister won't be there the majority of the time, she also really wants to find an apartment in walking distance to bustling downtown Brussels. Unfortunately, finding a centrally-located and spacious apartment at her $2,300-a-month budget is not going to be an easy assignment for real estate agent Julie Vermeulen. Watch as Esther decides what is better for her new life in Belgium, living in a lively location or having space for her sister's short stays when House Hunters International visits Brussels.",21-Nov-13,S61E04,"Space in the City of Brussels, Belgium",4,61,2013,"[('almost fifteen years', 4, 24, 'DATE'), ('Esther Ndichu', 26, 39, 'PERSON'), ('Atlanta', 51, 58, 'GPE'), ('Georgia', 141, 148, 'GPE'), ('Jennifer', 224, 232, 'PERSON'), ('England', 242, 249, 'GPE'), ('two', 259, 262, 'CARDINAL'), ('Esther', 301, 307, 'PERSON'), ('Brussels', 395, 403, 'GPE'), ('Esther', 432, 438, 'PERSON'), ('Jennifer', 521, 529, 'PERSON'), ('Belgium', 540, 547, 'GPE'), ('Jennifer', 572, 580, 'PERSON'), ('Esther', 614, 620, 'PERSON'), ('Esther', 711, 717, 'PERSON'), ('Brussels', 868, 876, 'GPE'), ('Julie Vermeulen', 1033, 1048, 'PERSON'), ('Esther', 1059, 1065, 'PERSON'), ('Belgium', 1109, 1116, 'GPE'), ('House Hunters International', 1196, 1223, 'ORG'), ('Brussels', 1231, 1239, 'GPE')]",Atlanta,United States,Brussels,Belgium,0,214
"When Teri McKenna was faced with an empty nest back home in Southern California, she decided it was time to live out one of her lifelong dreams. She moved to St. Thomas in the U.S. Virgin Islands, bought a Catamaran, and launched a charter boat business. The lifestyle change meant Terri would be working and living aboard the boat. Now, one year later, Terri still loves her boat, but she's starting to miss the conveniences of living on solid ground. She's looking for a condo on the island where she can live, and host her two grown sons when they come to visit. Local real estate agent Karen Korsgren shows Teri and her son Matt three properties close to her budget of $300,000. The first is listed for $315,000, and has two bedrooms and two baths and a great waterfront location. The second property has water views, but only one bedroom and one bath. But it's listed for the lower price of $240,000. The third condo is also just one bedroom and one bath. It's listed for just $205,000, but it does not have a water view at all. Which condo will give Teri the comfortable Island lifestyle she's looking for? Find out, when House Hunters International sails to the U.S. Virgin Islands.",6-Jun-10,S14E04,"Teri McKenna Has Lived and Worked on her Boat in St. Thomas for a Year, and She's Ready Now to Try Life on Solid Ground",4,14,2010,"[('Teri McKenna', 5, 17, 'PERSON'), ('Southern California', 60, 79, 'LOC'), ('one', 117, 120, 'CARDINAL'), ('Thomas', 162, 168, 'PERSON'), ('the U.S. Virgin Islands', 172, 195, 'GPE'), ('Catamaran', 206, 215, 'GPE'), ('Terri', 282, 287, 'PERSON'), ('one year later', 338, 352, 'DATE'), ('Terri', 354, 359, 'PERSON'), ('two', 526, 529, 'CARDINAL'), ('Karen Korsgren', 590, 604, 'PERSON'), ('Teri', 611, 615, 'PERSON'), ('Matt', 628, 632, 'PERSON'), ('three', 633, 638, 'CARDINAL'), ('300,000', 674, 681, 'MONEY'), ('first', 687, 692, 'ORDINAL'), ('315,000', 708, 715, 'MONEY'), ('two', 725, 728, 'CARDINAL'), ('two', 742, 745, 'CARDINAL'), ('second', 789, 795, 'ORDINAL'), ('only one', 826, 834, 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 847, 850, 'CARDINAL'), ('240,000', 897, 904, 'MONEY'), ('third', 910, 915, 'ORDINAL'), ('one', 935, 938, 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 951, 954, 'CARDINAL'), ('just $205,000', 977, 990, 'MONEY'), ('Teri', 1056, 1060, 'ORG'), ('Island', 1077, 1083, 'LOC'), ('House Hunters International', 1128, 1155, 'ORG'), ('the U.S. Virgin Islands', 1165, 1188, 'GPE')]",St. Thomas,United States,St. Thomas,United States,0,213
"A new job in Amsterdam has Californians Robert and Mary Jo Sandholm ready for a fresh start. After a bike accident forced Robert to stop working for seven years, Mary Jo stepped up and became the sole breadwinner for their family of six. Now that Robert's ready to return to the workforce as a Europe based marketing director for his company, he's excited to repay Mary Jo for helping him get back on his feet. She not only gets to return to the stay at home mom role she wants to fill, but Mary Jo also has the chance to recreate her childhood in the process. Growing up in the Irish countryside, she had an idyllic upbringing and she would love nothing more than for her family to have a similar experience in the Netherlands. The only problem with Mary Jo's dream, is the countryside is far from Robert's office and with his plan to cycle to work daily, finding the right balance of country charm and convenience, with space for their four young children, could be a challenge for real estate agent Roz Fremder. Find out if quaint will put practicality out to pasture, as House Hunters International and the Sandholms find a whole new outlook in the Netherlands capital of Amsterdam.",17-Oct-13,S59E07,A Second Chance in The Netherlands Capital of Amsterdam,7,59,2013,"[('Amsterdam', 13, 22, 'GPE'), ('Californians', 27, 39, 'NORP'), ('Robert', 40, 46, 'PERSON'), ('Mary Jo Sandholm', 51, 67, 'PERSON'), ('Robert', 122, 128, 'PERSON'), ('seven years', 149, 160, 'DATE'), ('Mary Jo', 162, 169, 'PERSON'), ('six', 233, 236, 'CARDINAL'), ('Robert', 247, 253, 'PERSON'), ('Europe', 294, 300, 'LOC'), ('Mary Jo', 365, 372, 'PERSON'), ('Mary Jo', 491, 498, 'PERSON'), ('Irish', 579, 584, 'NORP'), ('Netherlands', 716, 727, 'GPE'), (""Mary Jo's"", 751, 760, 'PERSON'), ('Robert', 799, 805, 'PERSON'), ('daily', 850, 855, 'DATE'), ('four', 938, 942, 'CARDINAL'), ('Roz Fremder', 1002, 1013, 'PERSON'), ('House Hunters International', 1075, 1102, 'ORG'), ('Sandholms', 1111, 1120, 'GPE'), ('Netherlands', 1153, 1164, 'GPE'), ('Amsterdam', 1176, 1185, 'GPE')]",California,United States,Amsterdam,Netherlands,0,213
"Antony and Stephanie met in 1989 in London through a mutual friend and were friends for eight years before they started dating. They were then married and were living together in London in a house Stephanie had bought when she was 21. Antony, a banker, has been offered a job in Switzerland and he and Stephanie have decided to take a step out of their comfort zone and move the family to Zurich. They believe that, along with a better job for Antony, it was a chance at better quality of life for them and their three daughters, Natalia, Katarina and Alexandra. Natalia, in particular, will benefit from the move. She is a special needs child and there is a school near Zurich that is known for the quality and care in which they help these kinds of students. They hope that all of these factors will make the transition and giant move they are making worth it. And they hope they can find the right home to suit their needs. Antony would like to buy something modern and sleek, while Stephanie would like an older, more traditional home. These issues, along with the culture change from England to Switzerland, will make this move challenging and exiting for their realtor Birgit Schonhofen.",21-Oct-09,S15E03,A House For Five In Switzerland (UK to Switzerland),3,15,2009,"[('Antony', 0, 6, 'GPE'), ('Stephanie', 11, 20, 'GPE'), ('1989', 28, 32, 'DATE'), ('London', 36, 42, 'GPE'), ('eight years', 88, 99, 'DATE'), ('London', 179, 185, 'GPE'), ('Stephanie', 197, 206, 'GPE'), ('21', 231, 233, 'DATE'), ('Antony', 235, 241, 'ORG'), ('Switzerland', 279, 290, 'GPE'), ('Stephanie', 302, 311, 'PERSON'), ('Zurich', 389, 395, 'GPE'), ('Antony', 444, 450, 'GPE'), ('three', 513, 518, 'CARDINAL'), ('Natalia', 530, 537, 'GPE'), ('Katarina', 539, 547, 'GPE'), ('Alexandra', 552, 561, 'PERSON'), ('Natalia', 563, 570, 'GPE'), ('Zurich', 671, 677, 'GPE'), ('Antony', 927, 933, 'ORG'), ('Stephanie', 986, 995, 'ORG'), ('England', 1089, 1096, 'GPE'), ('Switzerland', 1100, 1111, 'GPE'), ('Birgit Schonhofen', 1175, 1192, 'PERSON')]",London,England,Zurich,Switzerland,0,212
"Christopher has always wanted to live in the Caribbean, but he can't get his wife Tracy to make such a big commitment and leave their Mesa, Arizona home for good. So, they split the difference and decided to buy a vacation home on the Turks and Caicos Islands. The couple is looking into a Fractional Ownership home, which offers them the opportunity to share the ownership of a multi-million dollar home. It also means they could only stay for a specific number of weeks per year, perfect for Tracy. Christopher would still like to have the option of living in the home full time. Elite Home Destinations' Bill Bisanz steps in to help them decide if they should invest in a fractional or full ownership. Christopher and Tracy have a budget of $700,000 for a home that's a fractional and $2.5 million for one that they can own fully. They check out two fractionals: one that is available for $700,000 and offers an 8 week stay and the other is priced at $500,000 for a 10 week stay. Bill also shows them a sole ownership house listed for $2.5 million. It all boils down to how long Tracy and Christopher want to stay on the island. Who will have to compromise?",11-Apr-10,S13E03,Arizona Couple Seek a Vacation Home on the Turks and Caicos Islands (Turks and Caicos Vacation Home),3,13,2010,"[('Christopher', 0, 11, 'PERSON'), ('Caribbean', 45, 54, 'LOC'), ('Tracy', 82, 87, 'PERSON'), ('Mesa', 134, 138, 'ORG'), ('Arizona', 140, 147, 'GPE'), ('Turks', 235, 240, 'NORP'), ('Fractional Ownership', 290, 310, 'ORG'), ('-million dollar', 384, 399, 'MONEY'), ('weeks', 466, 471, 'DATE'), ('Tracy', 494, 499, 'ORG'), ('Christopher', 501, 512, 'PERSON'), (""Elite Home Destinations'"", 582, 606, 'ORG'), ('Bill Bisanz', 607, 618, 'PERSON'), ('Christopher', 705, 716, 'PERSON'), ('Tracy', 721, 726, 'PERSON'), ('700,000', 745, 752, 'MONEY'), ('$2.5 million', 788, 800, 'MONEY'), ('two', 849, 852, 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 866, 869, 'CARDINAL'), ('700,000', 893, 900, 'MONEY'), ('8 week', 915, 921, 'DATE'), ('500,000', 955, 962, 'MONEY'), ('10 week', 969, 976, 'DATE'), ('Bill', 983, 987, 'PERSON'), ('$2.5 million', 1038, 1050, 'MONEY'), ('Tracy', 1082, 1087, 'ORG'), ('Christopher', 1092, 1103, 'PERSON')]",Mesa,United States,Turks and Caicos Islands,England,0,211
"Michael and Samantha Parker, wanted to get away from the rat race and swap the precious hours they were spending inside their car stuck in LA traffic for a life away from LA, doing volunteer work somewhere new and exciting. Michael, is a musician who composes jazz, electronic and electro-dance music, but who was rarely able to indulge this passion with his demanding full time job, while Samantha is a foodie who loves challenging her culinary expertise by discovering and learning to cook with new ingredients.The couple spent a year planning their adventure, visiting Argentina, Chile and Peru in April of 2011, before settling on the capital of Tarija, Bolivia. Built during the Spanish colonial period, Tarija's customs and pace of life seem to have been frozen in time, with leisure time for family, friends and fun considered a priority rather than a luxury. However, when it comes to house hunting, tradition can often translate as tatty by modern standards and can quickly lose it's quaint charm when it comes to getting things done. Will expat realtor Martin Rattray be able to satisfy Michael and Samantha's property wishlist, while they survive on their savings? See what happens as this couple travel and take time out in Tarija, Bolivia.",18-Sep-12,S42E13,"Time Out in Tarija, Bolivia",13,42,2012,"[('Michael', 0, 7, 'PERSON'), ('Samantha Parker', 12, 27, 'PERSON'), ('the precious hours', 75, 93, 'TIME'), ('LA', 139, 141, 'GPE'), ('LA', 171, 173, 'GPE'), ('Michael', 224, 231, 'PERSON'), ('Samantha', 390, 398, 'PERSON'), ('a year', 530, 536, 'DATE'), ('Argentina', 572, 581, 'GPE'), ('Chile', 583, 588, 'GPE'), ('Peru', 593, 597, 'GPE'), ('April of 2011', 601, 614, 'DATE'), ('Tarija', 650, 656, 'ORG'), ('Bolivia', 658, 665, 'GPE'), ('Spanish', 684, 691, 'NORP'), ('Tarija', 709, 715, 'ORG'), ('Martin Rattray', 1063, 1077, 'PERSON'), ('Michael', 1097, 1104, 'PERSON'), ('Samantha', 1109, 1117, 'PERSON'), ('Tarija', 1236, 1242, 'GPE'), ('Bolivia', 1244, 1251, 'GPE')]",Los Angeles,United States,Tarija,Bolivia,0,208
"Almost twenty years ago, Natalie Devoy felt the overwhelming urge to flip the script on her quiet life in Northern Ireland. The relaxed pace had lost its luster and she made the bold decision to travel the globe. After stops in Europe along the way, Natalie finally found herself smack in the middle of energetic Hue, Vietnam, parlaying her hospitality background into teaching at a tourism school. In her time in Hue, she grew to love the vibrancy of the city but now she is coming full circle, returning to another sleepy fishing village, this time in Hoi An, Vietnam. She's going back to a lifestyle that she abandoned and it's all in the name of love for her fiance Julien. They met in Hoi An, where he runs a restaurant, and now it's where they want to own their first home together. The only issue is that in order to get Julien his coveted beach access at their $50,000 budget, they may have to settle on something decidedly dated, which will not please Natalie. Will they be able to find a seaside home that can meet her modern tastes? Find out when House Hunters International travels to the Ancient Town of Hoi An, Vietnam.",15-Oct-12,S44E04,"Down by the Seaside in Hoi An, Vietnam",4,44,2012,"[('Almost twenty years ago', 0, 23, 'DATE'), ('Natalie Devoy', 25, 38, 'PERSON'), ('Northern Ireland', 106, 122, 'GPE'), ('Europe', 228, 234, 'LOC'), ('Natalie', 250, 257, 'PERSON'), ('Hue', 313, 316, 'PERSON'), ('Vietnam', 318, 325, 'GPE'), ('Hue', 414, 417, 'PERSON'), ('Hoi An', 554, 560, 'GPE'), ('Vietnam', 562, 569, 'GPE'), ('Julien', 670, 676, 'PERSON'), ('Hoi', 690, 693, 'PERSON'), ('first', 768, 773, 'ORDINAL'), ('Julien', 828, 834, 'PERSON'), ('50,000', 870, 876, 'MONEY'), ('Natalie', 961, 968, 'PERSON'), ('House Hunters International', 1058, 1085, 'ORG'), ('the Ancient Town of Hoi An', 1097, 1123, 'FAC'), ('Vietnam', 1125, 1132, 'GPE')]",,Ireland,Hoi An,Vietnam,1,205
"Joe Cavanaugh has been racking up plenty of business class miles traveling between his company's offices in Atlanta, Georgia and Blackburn, England. When an opportunity to take a manager's position opened up in the U.K., for Joe, it was an easy decision because it is not only a major career boost, but also a chance to fulfill his lifelong dream of experiencing the world outside of Georgia. His wife, Mandy, however is not as enthused about the change. She's content with the modern conveniences and routine that her and their two young boys have in Cumming. Mandy is willing to support her husband's wishes but she is making it a goal to try and find the comforts of home in rural England. Unfortunately for Mandy, Joe wants a short commute to his office in the city center and trying to find a modern, spacious slice of America there, on their two thousand dollar a month budget is going to be challenging for real estate agent Haesel Abbott. Mandy may or may not be willing to get Georgia off her mind while Joe may have to miss out on getting an authentic English experience. Watch as House Hunters International takes a turn through tranquil Blackburn, England.",24-Jun-13,S53E02,"Creature Comforts in Blackburn, England",2,53,2013,"[('Joe Cavanaugh', 0, 13, 'PERSON'), ('Atlanta', 108, 115, 'GPE'), ('Georgia', 117, 124, 'GPE'), ('Blackburn', 129, 138, 'GPE'), ('England', 140, 147, 'GPE'), ('U.K.', 215, 219, 'GPE'), ('Joe', 225, 228, 'PERSON'), ('Georgia', 384, 391, 'GPE'), ('Mandy', 403, 408, 'PERSON'), ('two', 529, 532, 'CARDINAL'), ('Cumming', 552, 559, 'GPE'), ('Mandy', 561, 566, 'ORG'), ('England', 684, 691, 'GPE'), ('Mandy', 711, 716, 'PERSON'), ('Joe', 718, 721, 'PERSON'), ('America', 824, 831, 'GPE'), ('two thousand dollar', 848, 867, 'MONEY'), ('Haesel Abbott', 932, 945, 'PERSON'), ('Mandy', 947, 952, 'ORG'), ('Georgia', 986, 993, 'GPE'), ('Joe', 1013, 1016, 'PERSON'), ('English', 1062, 1069, 'LANGUAGE'), ('House Hunters International', 1091, 1118, 'ORG'), ('Blackburn', 1149, 1158, 'GPE'), ('England', 1160, 1167, 'GPE')]",Cumming,United States,Blackburn,England,0,205
"Married for 15 years, avid travelers Eyassu and Shontaye Abegaz always dreamed of living in another country. Though Eyassu was born in Ethiopia, he moved to the States for high school and has been living in the U.S. ever since. Growing tired of their hectic pace in Washington, DC the couple took a trip to Botswana and absolutely fell in love with the country: the culture, the people and the landscape. After Eyassu was offered a teaching job at a university in Gaborone, the couple had their chance to see their dream of living abroad come true. Luckily, Shontaye's job as a travel writer allows her to work anywhere. For Eyassu and Shontaye, Gaborone offers a little adventure and a much slower pace of life. But as the capital city of Botswana, it also has the hustle and bustle of one of Africa's fastest-growing cities and a booming housing market. Testing the waters before committing to purchasing a home, Eyassu and Shontaye have decided to start off renting and are counting on agent Kim Bekker to find them a nice rental encompassing their wish list of 3 to 4 bedrooms, 2 bathrooms and a pool within their budget of 1800 U.S. dollars a month.",18-Jul-11,S24E08,"Slower-pace of life in Gaborone, Botswana",8,24,2011,"[('15 years', 12, 20, 'DATE'), ('Eyassu', 37, 43, 'GPE'), ('Shontaye Abegaz', 48, 63, 'PERSON'), ('Eyassu', 116, 122, 'ORG'), ('Ethiopia', 135, 143, 'GPE'), ('U.S.', 211, 215, 'GPE'), ('Washington, DC', 266, 280, 'GPE'), ('Botswana', 307, 315, 'GPE'), ('Eyassu', 411, 417, 'ORG'), ('Gaborone', 464, 472, 'ORG'), ('Shontaye', 558, 566, 'ORG'), ('Eyassu', 625, 631, 'ORG'), ('Shontaye', 636, 644, 'ORG'), ('Gaborone', 646, 654, 'ORG'), ('Botswana', 740, 748, 'GPE'), ('Africa', 794, 800, 'LOC'), ('Eyassu', 915, 921, 'GPE'), ('Shontaye', 926, 934, 'ORG'), ('Kim Bekker', 995, 1005, 'PERSON'), ('3 to 4', 1065, 1071, 'CARDINAL'), ('2', 1082, 1083, 'CARDINAL'), ('1800 U.S. dollars', 1128, 1145, 'MONEY')]","Washington, DC",United States,Gaborone,Botswana,0,204
